BRUCE: Rachel, let me see.
布魯斯: 雷切爾，我看看
- Can I see? - Finders keepers. And I found it.
-我能看看嗎？ -誰找的歸誰，是我找到的
In my garden.
可這是我家的花園
Finders keepers.
誰找到歸誰
Bruce?
布魯斯?
[WOOD SNAPPING]
[木頭斷裂聲]
[THUD]
[砰]
Bruce?
布魯斯？
Mom! Mr. Alfred!
媽媽！艾爾弗雷德先生！
[WHIMPERS]
[嗚咽聲]
[SCREAMING]
[喊叫聲]
[MEN SCREAMING IN DISTANCE]
[有人遠處喊叫]
Did you have dream?
做夢了，對吧
Nightmare.
噩夢
Worse than this place?
比這地方還糟嗎？
[MAN SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE OVER P.A.]
[好了，吃飯了]
MAN [WHISPERS]: They are going to fight you.
他們要揍你
- Again? - Until they kill you.
-又來了？ -一直到把你殺了為止
Can they kill me before breakfast?
他們在早餐前能殺掉我嗎？
You are in hell, little man.
小子，你這是在地獄裡
And I am the devil.
而我就是魔鬼
You're not the devil.
你不是魔鬼
You're practice.
隻不過是我練身手用的
[GRUNTING]
[呼嚕聲]
[GUNSHOTS]
[槍聲]
GUARD: Solitary.
關禁閉
- Why? - For protection.
-為什麼？ -為了保護你
- I don't need protection. - Protection for them.
-我...我不需要保護 -那就保護了他們
[MEN GROANING]
[呻吟聲]
Get in.
進去
DUCARD: Are you so desperate to fight criminals...
杜卡德: 你如此瘋狂地要向罪惡宣戰 為此不惜進監獄
...that you lock yourself in to take them on one at a time?
...就是為了有足夠的時間 一個個收拾他們
Actually, there were seven of them.
事實上這次有...七個
I counted six, Mr. Wayne.
我數的是六個，韋恩先生
How do you know my name?
你怎麼知道我的名字？
The world is too small for someone like Bruce Wayne to disappear...
對於像布魯斯.韋恩這樣的人來說...
...no matter how deep he chooses to sink.
...要想在這麼小的世界裡消失 不太容易
Who are you?
你是誰？
My name is merely Ducard, but I speak for Ra's al Ghul...
我是杜卡德 我是拉.阿勒古爾的代言人
...a man greatly feared by the criminal underworld.
...他是令地下罪惡世界 聞風喪膽的人物
A man who can offer you a path.
他將為你提供一條出路
What makes you think I need a path?
你為什麼認為我需要出路？
Someone like you is only here by choice.
像你這樣的人來到這 是經過精心挑選的
You have been exploring the criminal fraternity...
你已經深入地了解了罪惡世界...
...but whatever your original intentions...
...但是無論有什麼樣的初衷...
...you have become truly lost.
...你最終都會感到迷失
And what path can Ra's al Ghul offer?
那麼拉.阿勒古爾又 能提供什麼樣的出路呢？
The path of a man who shares his hatred of evil...
一條為痛恨邪惡者提供的出路
...and wishes to serve true justice.
...願意為公正獻身者的出路
The path of the League of Shadows.
影子軍團出路
[CHUCKLES]
[笑聲]
- You're vigilantes. - No, no, no.
-你是治安維持會的？ -不，不是
A vigilante is just a man lost in the scramble for his own gratification.
治安維持會的人是為了一己之滿足
He can be destroyed or locked up.
很容易喪失斗志，甚至連自己都陷於不義
But if you make yourself more than just a man...
但是...如果你能夠超越自我
...if you devote yourself to an ideal...
把自己獻身於某種信念
...and if they can't stop you...
如果任何人都無法阻止你
...then you become something else entirely.
你就會化身為某種永恆的東西
Which is?
什麼東西？
Legend, Mr. Wayne.
某種傳奇，韋恩先生
Tomorrow, you will be released.
明天你將被釋放
If you are bored of brawling with thieves and want to achieve something...
什麼時候你厭倦了與一群小混蛋們周旋的時候 當你想成就一番事業的時候...
...there is a rare blue flower that grows on the eastern slopes.
喜馬拉雅東邊山腳下生長著
Pick one of these flowers.
一種罕見的藍色罌粟花 將向你召喚採一枝花
If you can carry it to the top of the mountain...
你帶著花爬到山頂...
...you may find what you were looking for in the first place.
...就能找到你所需要的東西
And what was I looking for?
那麼 我需要的是什麼呢？
Only you can know that.
答案你自己知道
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
[卡嗒聲]
You turn back. You go back.
你又繞回來 沒錯，你又繞回來啦
BRUCE: Ra's al Ghul?
布魯斯：我要找拉.阿勒古爾
DUCARD: Wait.
杜卡德：請稍等
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[烏爾都語]
[TRANSLATING] What are you seeking?
[翻譯] 你在尋找什麼？
I seek...
我在尋找...
...the means to fight injustice.
...戰勝非正義的方法
To turn fear...
用恐懼...
...against those who prey on the fearful.
...戰勝恐懼的方法
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[烏爾都語]
DUCARD [TRANSLATING]: To manipulate the fears in others...
杜卡德 [翻譯]: 為了掌控他人的恐懼...
...you must first master your own.
...你必須駕馭自己的恐懼
Are you ready to begin?
你准備好了嗎？
I can... I can barely stand.
我....我快站不住了
Death does not wait for you to be ready!
死亡並不會給你喘息的機會的
Death is not considerate or fair!
死亡沒有同情心，也不會公正
And make no mistake, here you face death.
為了准確無誤 現在你必須面對死亡
Tiger.
虎術
Jujitsu.
柔術
Panther.
豹術
You're skilled. But this is not a dance.
你已經學到了這些武藝 但是這可不是當舞蹈跳著玩
And you are afraid.
而且你心存恐懼
But not of me.
但不是我
Tell us, Mr. Wayne...
告訴我，韋恩先生...
...what do you fear?
...你懼怕的是什麼？
[BATS SQUEAKING]
[蝙蝠嘯叫聲]
Bruce?
布魯斯？
It's okay. It's okay.
沒事了沒事了
You'll be okay.
你會沒事的
ALFRED: Will we be needing an ambulance, Master Wayne?
艾爾弗雷德： 要不要叫救護車，韋恩大人
THOMAS: No, I'll set the bone and take him for an x-ray later.
托馬斯：不必了，我可以給他接骨 然後帶他去照個X光片子就行了
ALFRED: Very good, sir.
艾爾弗雷德：那好，先生
- I'm very sorry, sir. I've told... THOMAS: Don't worry. It's fine.
-我很抱歉 先生 我已經... -托馬斯：不必擔心，他沒事的
ALFRED: Took quite a fall, didn't we, Master Bruce?
艾爾弗雷德: 摔得夠嗆吧，布魯斯少爺
THOMAS: And why do we fall?
托馬斯: 到底是怎麼摔下去的？
So we can learn to pick ourselves up.
那兒摔倒的就從哪兒爬起來
Just a little fall. It's just a small fracture.
摔了下，小小的骨折而已
THOMAS: The bats again?
托馬斯:又夢見蝙蝠了？
You know why they attacked you, don't you?
你知道他們為什麼襲擊你嗎？
- They were afraid of you. - Afraid of me?
-因為他們害怕你 -害怕我？
All creatures feel fear.
所有的生物都會感到恐懼
Even the scary ones?
最厲害的動物也會？
Especially the scary ones.
表面厲害的動物更會害怕
I got something to show you.
我有些東西要給你看
- You think your mother will like them? - Yeah.
-你媽媽會喜歡？ -會的
- I think it's time to get up. - Maybe.
-是不是該起床了？ -也許吧
THOMAS: No going back to bed.
托馬斯:算了，還是繼續躺著吧
Did you build this train, Dad?
這火車是你造的嗎？
Gotham's been good to our family, but the city's been suffering.
哥特城的人民對我們的家族有恩 但是這個城市正在經歷痛苦
People less fortunate than us have been enduring very hard times.
不如我們富有的人們日子好過 所以我們建造了一條提供
So we built a new, cheap, public transportation system to unite the city.
廉價服務的新的公共交通系統 重新把人們凝聚起來
And at the center...
而中心就是...
...Wayne Tower.
...韋恩大廈
BRUCE: Is that where you work? - No, I work at the hospital.
布魯斯:那是你工作的地方嗎？ -不，我在醫院工作
I leave the running of our company to much better men.
我把公司交給 更善於經營的人去管理
- Better? - Well...
-善於經營？ -就是...
...more interested men.
...就是對經營更感興趣的人
[PERFORMERS SINGING]
[歌聲響起]
[ORCHESTRA PLAYING]
[管弦樂演奏]
[GASPING]
[喘氣聲]
Can we go?
咱們可以走了嗎？
Please.
求你了
Okay. Let's go.
好吧，咱們走
- What's wrong, Bruce? - No, no. It was me.
-怎麼了，布魯斯？ -不不 是因為我
I just needed some fresh air.
我想呼吸點新鮮空氣
A little bit of opera goes a long way. Right, Bruce?
你是不是覺得這個歌劇有點長？ 布魯斯？
Come on. Let's go.
來吧 咱們走
Wallets, jewelry. Come on, fast.
錢包 首飾 趕快拿出來
THOMAS: That's fine. CHILL: Fast.
托馬斯:好的 切爾:快點
Take it easy.
別緊張
Here you go.
給你
It's fine. It's fine.
好的 好的
Now just take it and go.
拿去 走吧
- I said, jewelry. THOMAS: Hey...
-我說了 把首飾也拿出來 拿出來 托馬斯:嘿...
[GUNSHOT]
[槍聲]
[MARTHA SCREAMING]
[瑪撒大叫]
MARTHA: Thomas!
瑪撒:托馬斯
[GUNSHOT]
[槍聲]
THOMAS [WHISPERING]: Bruce.
托馬斯[細語]: 布魯斯
It's okay.
沒關系
Don't be afraid.
你別害怕
[CHATTERING]
[照相機喀嚓作響]
Is this your father's?
這是你父親的嗎？
It's okay.
沒事了
Come here.
過來
There you go.
穿上
It's okay.
沒事了
都過去了
LOEB: Gordon.
雷波:戈登
Hey.
嘿
Good news.
好消息
We got him, son.
我們抓住他了，孩子
You're in excellent hands.
你就放心吧
We'll be watching the empire.
我們會幫你經管好企業的
When you grow up, it'll be waiting for you.
等你長大了 我們會把它好好交到你手裡
I thought I might prepare a little supper.
我想應該准備些晚飯了
- Very well. - Alfred?
-好吧 -艾爾弗雷德
- Yes, Master Bruce? - It was my fault, Alfred.
-什麼事，少爺？ -都怪我，艾爾弗雷德
- I made them leave the theater. - No.
-是我讓他們提前離開歌劇院的 -不...
- lf I hadn't gotten scared... - It was nothing that you did.
-我要是不害怕的話... -這事跟你沒關系
It was him, and him alone.
全都是那凶手的錯 都是他
Do you understand?
你明白嗎？
I miss them, Alfred. I miss them so much.
我想他們，艾爾弗雷德 我真的想他們
So do I, Master Bruce.
我也一樣，布魯斯少爺
So do I.
我也一樣
DUCARD: And do you still feel responsible for your parents' death?
杜卡德:你還為你父母的死感到自責嗎？
My anger outweighs my guilt.
我的憤怒超過了我的自責
Come.
來吧
You have learned to bury your guilt with anger.
你已經學會了用憤怒淹沒自責
I will teach you to confront it and to face the truth.
我來教你如何正確面對現實
You know how to fight six men. We can teach you how to engage 600.
你知道如何戰勝六個對手 我們可以教會你如何打敗六百個敵人
You know how to disappear.
你懂得如何潛伏
We can teach you to become truly invisible.
我們可以教你如何隱身
Invisible?
隱身？
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[阿偉]
The ninja understands that invisibility is a matter of patience and agility.
忍者都要明白隱身 最重要的是耐心和機敏
[GRUNTING]
[啊...]
Always mind your surroundings.
任何時候都要保持警惕
Ninjitsu employs explosive powders.
忍者講究實用小型炸彈
- As weapons? - Or distractions.
-當作武器？ -或者當作煙霧彈
Theatricality and deception are powerful agents.
戲劇性的騙術是很有效的手段
You must become more than just a man in the mind of your opponent.
你必須超越你的對手對你的設想
[MAN SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[我是冤枉的]
BRUCE: Who is he? - He was a farmer.
布魯斯:他是誰？ -他是一個農夫
Then he tried to take his neighbor's land and became a murderer.
為了霸佔鄰居的土地 他變成了一個凶手
- Now he is a prisoner. - What'll happen to him?
-現在被監禁了 -打算怎麼處置他？
Justice. Crime cannot be tolerated.
正義，邪惡不能被寬恕
Criminals thrive on the indulgence of society's understanding.
要知道罪犯的所作所為 是對社會同情心的侮辱
Your parents' death was not your fault.
你父母的死並不是你的錯
It was your father's.
而是你父親的錯
Anger does not change the fact that your father failed to act.
你發火也沒用 無法改變你父親沒有反抗的事實
- The man had a gun. - Would that stop you?
-那個人手裡有槍 -槍能阻止你反抗嗎？
I've had training.
我是受過訓練的人
The training is nothing!
這跟訓練毫無關系
Will is everything!
主觀決定一切
The will to act.
付出行動的意願
Yield.
投降吧
You haven't beaten me.
你並沒有打敗我
You have sacrificed sure footing for a killing stroke.
你在襲擊我之前 腳下已經失控了
DUCARD: Rub your chest.
杜卡德:搓搓胸口
Your arms will take care of themselves.
你的胳膊一會就暖和了
You are stronger than your father.
你比你父親要強壯
You didn't know my father.
你並不認識我父親
But I know the rage that drives you.
但是我了解你內心的憤怒
That impossible anger strangling the grief...
這種無法抑制的憤怒 在你的內心郁結糾纏
...until the memory of your loved one is just...
...直到將你所愛的人的懷念...
...poison in your veins.
...轉化為你血液中的毒素
And one day, you catch yourself wishing the person you loved had never existed...
總有一天，你會希望你所愛的人 從來都沒有存在過...
...so you'd be spared your pain.
...隻有這樣你才可以化解你的痛楚
I wasn't always here in the mountains.
我並沒有一直住在山裡
Once, I had a wife.
我曾有個
My great love.
相愛的妻子
She was taken from me.
她離開了我
Like you, I was forced to learn there are those without decency...
像你一樣 我必須毫無選擇地 面對這種殘酷的事實...
...who must be fought without hesitation, without pity.
...必須學會無情的反擊
Your anger gives you great power.
你的憤怒會帶給你巨大的力量
But if you let it, it will destroy you...
但是如果你不加以控制，他會毀掉你...
...as it almost did me.
...我差一點就被毀掉
- What stopped it? - Vengeance.
-怎麼阻止他？ -復仇
That's no help to me.
這點對我無效
Why, Bruce?
為什麼 布魯斯？
Why could you not avenge your parents?
你為什麼不能為你的父母復仇?
Will you be heading back to Princeton after the hearing, sir...
參加了聽證會以後  您馬上會普林斯頓去嗎？
...or can I persuade you to stay on for a day or two?
...或許我能說服您在這兒多住幾天
BRUCE: I'm not heading back at all.
布魯斯:我不會回去了
ALFRED: You don't like it there? - I like it fine.
艾爾弗雷德:你不喜歡那裡？ -我很喜歡
They just don't feel the same way.
隻是和以前的感覺不太一樣
- I've prepared the master bedroom. - No.
-我已經把老爺的臥室給您收拾好了 -不必了
My room will be fine.
我自己的房間就很好
ALFRED: With all due respect, sir, Wayne Manor is your house.
艾爾弗雷德:恕我直言韋恩庄園屬於您
BRUCE: No, Alfred, it's my father's house.
布魯斯:不 艾爾弗雷德 它屬於我父親的
- Your father is dead. - This place is a mausoleum.
-你父親不在了 -這裡是一座墳墓
If I have my way, I'll pull the damn thing down brick by brick.
如果依著我 我恨不能把這房子拆了
This house, Master Wayne, has sheltered six generations of your family.
這棟房子，韋恩大人 蔭庇了您的家族六代人了
Why do you give a damn, Alfred? It's not your family.
又不是你的家人，艾爾弗雷德 你干嘛那麼在乎啊？
I give a damn because a good man once made me responsible...
我之所以在乎， 那是因為有一位好人他托付我
...for what was most precious to him...
...讓我照顧他一生中...
...in the whole world.
...最珍愛的一個人
Miss Dawes has offered to drive you to the hearing.
道斯小姐打算開車送您去聽證會
She probably hopes to talk you out of going.
他也許私下裡有話要對你說
BRUCE: Should I just bury the past out there with my parents, Alfred?
布魯斯:我難道要把我過去的一切 也和我的父母一同埋葬嘛？艾爾弗雷德
I wouldn't presume to tell you what to do with your past, sir.
我無法告訴你應該如何對待你的過去
Just know that there are those of us who care about what you do with your future.
但是我們這些人都很關系 你如何對待您的未來
Haven't given up on me yet?
你還沒有放棄我嗎？
Never.
永遠不會
Alfred still keeps the condensed milk on the top shelf.
艾爾弗雷德還把煉乳放在架子的頂層？
Hasn't he noticed you're tall enough to reach now?
難道他沒有注意到你已經長高了嗎？
Old habits die hard, I guess.
我看是舊習難改了
- Never used to stop us anyway. - No, it didn't.
-不過這個方法從來沒有阻止過咱們 -就是的
How's your mom?
你媽媽怎麼樣？
She misses this place.
她很懷念這裡
So do I.
我也是
Yeah.
是呀
But it's nothing without the people who made it what it was.
不過已經物是人非了
- Now there's only Alfred. - And you.
-現在這裡就剩艾爾弗雷德 -還有你
- I'm not staying, Rachel. - You're just back for the hearing.
-我不會留下來的，雷切爾 -你是來參加聽證會的
Bruce, I don't suppose there's any way to convince you not to come.
布魯斯 我知道 誰也無法阻止你回來 我知道
Someone at this proceeding...
聽證會上必須...
...should stand for my parents.
...有人代表我的父母
We all loved your parents, Bruce.
我們都很愛你的父母 布魯斯
- What Chill did is unforgivable. - Then why is your boss letting him go?
-切爾的所作所為是不可饒恕的 -那為什麼你的上司要放走他
In prison, he shared a cell with Carmine Falcone.
在監獄裡他和法爾科內 共用一部手機
He learned things, and he will testify in exchange for early parole.
他聽到了一些秘密 他想用此作為交換 提前出獄
Rachel, this man killed my parents.
雷切爾，這個人殺了我的雙親
I cannot let that pass.
我是永遠無法忘記這一切的
And I need you to understand that, please.
我需要你的理解 雷切爾
Okay.
好吧
FINCH: The depression hit working people, like Mr. Chill, hardest of all.
芬奇:經濟大蕭條對切爾先生 這樣的工人打擊最大
His crime was appalling, yes, but it was motivated not by greed...
他的罪行雖然駭人聽聞 但是其犯罪的動機並非出於貪婪...
...but by desperation.
...而是出於絕望
Given the 14 years served, as well as his extraordinary level of cooperation...
同時鑒於他已經在獄中服刑了十四年...
...with one of this office's most important investigations...
...加之這次他對地區檢察官的通力配合...
...we strongly endorse his petition for early release.
...我們完全贊同提前解除他的刑期
FADEN: Mr. Chill?
法頓:切爾先生
CHILL: Your Honor...
切爾: 尊敬的大人...
...not a day goes by that I don't wish I could take back what I did.
...沒有一天我不是生活在悔恨當中
Sure, I was desperate, like a lot of people back then...
是的 我是很絕望 像那時的許多人一樣...
...but that don't change what I did.
...但是這並不能改變我所作的一切
FADEN: I gather there is a member of the Wayne family here today.
法頓:我想今天有一位 韋恩家族的成員也在場
Has he got anything to say?
他有話要說嗎？
WOMAN 1: He's coming out the side! MAN 1: He's coming out the side, guys!
女記者1：他出來了 男記者1：他出來了 就是他
[CLAMORING]
[叫嚷聲]
MAN 2: Bruce Wayne!
男記者2：布魯斯.韋恩！
WOMAN 2: Joe! Hey, Joe!
女記者2：喬！嘿！喬
Falcone says hi.
法爾科內向你問候
[GUNSHOT]
[槍聲]
[PEOPLE SHOUTING]
[人們尖叫聲]
RACHEL: Come on, Bruce.
雷切爾：走吧，布魯斯
We don't need to see this.
我們別看了
I do.
可我想看
RACHEL: The DA couldn't understand why Judge Faden insisted...
雷切爾:地方檢察官不可能明白
...on making the hearing public.
...法官為什麼要舉行公開聽證會
Falcone paid him off to get Chill out in the open.
其實是法爾科內收買了他 使切爾暴露在公共場合
Maybe I should thank them.
也許我們還應該感謝他們呢
- You don't mean that. - What if I do, Rachel?
-我不相信你真的這麼想 -我要是真的這麼想呢 雷切爾？
My parents deserved justice.
我父母應該得到公正
You're not talking about justice. You're talking about revenge.
其實你在談論的 不是公正 而是報仇
- Sometimes, they're the same. - No, they're never the same.
-有時他們就是一回事 -不 它根本就不是一回事
Justice is about harmony. Revenge is about you making yourself feel better.
公正是為了平息矛盾 而報仇是為了平息自己的憤怒
- It's why we have an impartial system. - Your system is broken.
-這就是為什麼我們要建立公正的制度 -遺憾的是你的制度已經失效了
[TIRES SCREECHING AND HORNS HONKING]
[輪胎磨地聲和汽車喇叭聲]
You care about justice? Look beyond your own pain, Bruce.
你真的在乎公正嗎？ 還是隻在乎你自己的痛苦？
This city is rotting.
這個城市已經腐朽墮落了
They talk about the depression as if it's history. It's not.
他們說起經濟大蕭條 好像已經是過去的歷史
Things are worse than ever here.
其實並非如此，這的一切比以往更糟
Falcone floods our streets with crime and drugs...
法爾科內用罪惡和毒品 摧毀了我們的城市...
...preying on the desperate, creating new Joe Chills every day.
...每天都在制造喬.切爾 這樣的亡命徒 你知道嗎？
Falcone may not have killed your parents, Bruce...
也許法爾科內並沒有 親手殺死你的父母...
...but he's destroying everything that they stood for.
... 但他們摧毀了賴以生存的基礎
You wanna thank him for that? Here you go.
你要是感謝他們就在這
We all know where to find him. As long as he keeps the bad people rich...
大家都知道能在哪裡找到這些為富不仁之人...
...and the good people scared, no one'll touch him.
...大家都近鬼神而遠之
Good people like your parents, who'll stand against injustice, they're gone.
像你父母一樣站起來維護 正義的好人都沒有了
What chance does Gotham have when the good people do nothing?
當所有的好人都選擇沉默的時候？ 這個城市還有什麼希望...
- I'm not one of your good people, Rachel. - What do you mean?
-我並不是你所謂的好人 雷切爾 -你是什麼意思？
All these years, I wanted to kill him.
這麼多年以來 我一直想殺死他
Now I can't.
而現在卻不同了
Your father would be ashamed of you.
你父親會為你感到恥辱的
You're taller than you look in the tabloids, Mr. Wayne.
你比報紙上看得高，韋恩先生
No gun? I'm insulted.
沒帶槍？真是對我的侮辱
- You could've just sent a thank-you note. - I didn't come here to thank you.
-你托人帶一封感謝信就行了 -我不是來表示感謝的
I came to show you that not everyone in Gotham's afraid of you.
我要讓你知道 並不是所有哥特人都懼怕你
Only those who know me, kid.
隻有認識我的人才怕我，孩子
Look around you. You'll see two councilmen...
你看看吧 這兒有兩位市議院的官員...
...a union official, couple off-duty cops...
...一位眾議院官員 幾位警官...
...and a judge.
...還有一位法官
I wouldn't have a second's hesitation of blowing your head off in front of them.
現在我可以毫不猶豫地 把你的腦袋轟掉
Now, that's power you can't buy.
就當著他們的面，這就是你無法企及的能量
That's the power of fear.
這就是你恐懼的來源
I'm not afraid of you.
我並不懼怕你
Because you think you got nothing to lose.
那是因為你以為自己 沒有什麼怕失去的
But you haven't thought it through.
可惜你想得不仔細
You haven't thought about your lady friend in the DA's office.
你沒有考慮到 你那在市檢察院工作的女友
You haven't thought about your old butler. Bang!
還有你的老管家 \u5623
People from your world...
來自你們那個世界的人...
...have so much to lose.
...有太多害怕失去的東西
Now, you think because your mommy and your daddy got shot...
你以為 一位你的媽媽爸爸被殺了...
...you know about the ugly side of life, but you don't.
...你就了解人生的殘酷 其實你還差得遠
You've never tasted desperate.
你還不知道什麼叫做絕望
You're... You're Bruce Wayne, the prince of Gotham.
你是布魯斯.韋恩 哥特城的王子
You'd have to go 1000 miles to meet someone who didn't know your name.
千裡之外你才體會得到 無人知曉的滋味
So don't come here with your anger, trying to prove something to yourself.
所以你不要帶著你的憤怒到這裡來 以此證實你的能力
This is a world you'll never understand.
這個世界你永遠無法了解
And you always fear...
因為你無法了解...
...what you don't understand.
...所以你才會恐懼
All right.
就這樣
Yeah, you got spirit, kid. I'll give you that.
好，我得這麼說 你有種，小子
More than your old man anyway.
比你老子有種
In the joint, Chill told me about the night he killed your parents.
在牢裡 切爾告訴我說 那天晚上他去殺你父母的時候
He said your father begged for mercy.
你父親乞求他饒命
Begged.
乞求
Like a dog.
像一條狗一樣
Should've tipped better.
應該多給點他小費
- For what? - Your jacket.
-這是干嘛？ -買你的外套
Okay.
好吧
Hey, hey, hey. Let me have it. It's a nice coat.
嘿嘿嘿 把它給我 這件外套挺不錯的
Be careful who sees you with that.
別讓人看見你穿它
- They're gonna come looking for me. - Who?
-他們不會放過我 -誰呀？
BRUCE: Everyone.
布魯斯:所有人
It's...
這外套....
It's a nice coat.
真不錯
DUCARD: When you lived among the criminals, did you start to pity them?
杜卡德:當你生活在罪犯當中 你會不會開始同情他們？
BRUCE: The first time I stole so that I wouldn 't starve, yes.
布魯斯:當我第一次為了 不被餓死而偷竊的時候，是的
I lost many assumptions about the simple nature of right and wrong.
我失去了許多 判斷對與錯的能力
And when I traveled...
當我四處旅行的時候...
...I learned the fear before a crime...
...我體會到了那種在罪惡面前的恐懼感...
...and the thrill of success.
...以及犯罪後的快感
[MAN SHOUTING IN MANDARIN]
[站住，不許動...]
BRUCE: But I never became one of them.
布魯斯:但是我從未變成他們中的一員
[OFFICER 1 SPEAKING MANDARIN]
[長官，他不說他的名字]
OFFICER 2: Fool. What do I care what your name is? You're a criminal.
我才不管你叫什麼名字呢 你就是一個罪犯
[SPEAKING MANDARIN] I'm not a criminal
[我不是罪犯]
OFFICER 2: Tell that to the guy who owned these.
那你去跟這些貨物的主人說吧 [韋恩企業，中國制造]
DUCARD: You've traveled the world to understand the criminal mind...
杜卡德:周游世界之後 你了解了罪犯的心理...
...and conquer your fears.
...並且戰勝了內心的恐懼
But a criminal is not complicated.
但是罪犯並不可怕
And what you really fear is inside yourself.
真正可怕的是你的內心
You fear your own power.
你懼怕你內心的能量
You fear your anger...
懼怕你的憤怒...
...the drive to do great or terrible things.
...它會驅使你做出 或偉大或可怕的事情
Now you must journey inwards.
現在你必須開始心靈的旅程
You are ready.
你已經准備好了
Breathe.
深呼吸
吸
Breathe in your fears.
在你的恐懼中呼吸
Face them.
面對他們
To conquer fear, you must become fear.
若想戰勝恐懼 你必須化身為恐懼
You must bask in the fear of other men.
在他人的恐懼中體會到樂趣
And men fear most what they cannot see.
人最懼怕的就是看不見的東西
You have to become a terrible thought.
你要化作一種可怕的想法
A wraith.
一個幻影
You have to become an idea!
化作一個意念
Feel terror cloud your senses.
去感受恐懼蒙蔽了你的意識
Feel its power to distort.
感受它扭曲的力量
To control.
控制一切的力量
And know that this power can be yours.
並且相信這種力量屬於你
Embrace your worst fear.
擁抱你內心最大的恐懼
Become one with the darkness.
化作黑暗的一部分
[BATS SQUEAKING]
[蝙蝠嘯叫聲]
Focus.
集中精力
Concentrate.
專著
Master your senses.
控制你的意識
You cannot leave any sign.
你不能留下任何破綻
BRUCE: I haven't.
布魯斯:我沒有
Impressive.
真不錯
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[烏爾都語]
DUCARD [TRANSLATING]: We have purged your fear.
杜卡德[翻譯道] : 我們清除了你的恐懼
You are ready to lead these men.
你現在可以統領這些武士了
You are ready to become a member of the League of Shadows.
你已經准備好 變成影子軍團的一員啦
But first, you must demonstrate your commitment to justice.
但首先 你必須證明你對正義的信念
[SPEAKS FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[帶上來]
No.
不
I'm no executioner.
我不是劊子手
DUCARD: Your compassion is a weakness your enemies will not share.
同情心是你的弱點 而你的敵人卻沒有
That's why it's so important.
正因為如此，它才更重要
It separates us from them.
正是他使我有別於敵人
You want to fight criminals. This man is a murderer.
你要面對的是罪惡 這個人是凶手
- This man should be tried. DUCARD: By whom?
-這個人應該由法律制裁 杜卡德:由誰呢？
Corrupt bureaucrats?
腐敗的官僚？
Criminals mock society's laws.
罪犯根本就無視社會法律
You know this better than most.
這一點你比任何人都更了解
RA'S A GHUL: You cannot lead these men...
拉.阿勒古爾: 除非你做好准備...
...unless you are prepared to do what is necessary to defeat evil.
...不惜一切戰勝邪惡 否則你無法統領這些戰士
And where would I be leading these men?
我統領他們所向何方呢？
Gotham.
哥特城
As Gotham's favored son...
作為哥特城之子...
...you will be ideally placed to strike at the heart of criminality.
...你將是戰斗在罪惡中心的 最理想的人選
- How? - Gotham's time has come.
-具體怎樣？ -哥特城的末日已經來臨
Like Constantinople or Rome before it...
就像當年的君士坦丁堡或者羅馬一樣...
...the city has become a breeding ground for suffering and injustice.
...整個城市已經變成 苦難和非正義的溫床
It is beyond saving and must be allowed to die.
它已經無可救藥 必須壽終正寢了
This is the most important function of the League of Shadows.
這是影子軍團最重要的使命
It is one we've performed for centuries.
為了這個使命 我們已經演練了數個世紀了
Gotham...
哥特城...
...must be destroyed.
...必須被摧毀
You can't believe in this.
這真是難以置信
Ra's al Ghul rescued us from the darkest corners of our own hearts.
拉.阿拉古爾曾經 在我們最絕望的時刻救過我們
What he asks in return is the courage to do what is necessary.
作為交換他要求我們不惜一切 去做必須的事情
I will go back to Gotham and I will fight men like this...
我會回到哥特城照此戰斗...
...but I will not become an executioner.
...但是我絕不能讓 自己成為一名劊子手
Bruce, please.
布魯斯
For your own sake, there is no turning back.
為了你自己 已經無法回頭了
- What are you doing? - What's necessary, my friend.
-你在干什麼? -做我必須做的事，朋友
[EXPLOSIONS]
[爆炸聲]
[BRUCE SCREAMING]
[布魯斯叫聲]
I will tell him you saved his life.
我要告訴他 你救了他的命
Master Wayne, you've been gone a long time.
韋恩少爺 你離開了有一段時間了
- Yes, I have. - You look very fashionable.
-是啊 -看起來很時髦，就是
Apart from the mud.
身上有些泥
Are you coming back to Gotham for long, sir?
您這次打算在哥特城 多住一段時間嗎？
As long as it takes.
能呆多久就呆多久
I want to show the people...
我要讓哥特人明白...
...their city doesn't belong to the criminals and the corrupt.
...這個城市並不屬於罪惡和腐敗
In the depression, your father nearly bankrupted Wayne Enterprises...
大蕭條時期  你父親...
...combating poverty.
...傾其所有與貧窮斗爭
He believed his example could inspire the wealthy of Gotham to save their city.
他堅信他的榜樣的力量可以激勵 哥特的富人起來拯救他們的城市
Did it?
有用嗎？
In a way.
某種程度上
Their murder shocked the wealthy and the powerful into action.
他們的死刺激了 那些富有的人採取行動
People need dramatic examples to shake them out of apathy.
我們必須打破 人們的這種冷漠態度
I can't do that as Bruce Wayne.
以布魯斯.韋恩的名義 做不到這點
As a man...
我作為一個普通人...
...I'm flesh and blood, I can be ignored, destroyed.
...是有血有肉的 會被忽略 會被輕易摧毀
But as a symbol...
但是如果作為一種象征....
As a symbol, I can be incorruptible.
作為一種象征的話
- I can be everlasting. - What symbol?
-會成為不朽 -什麼象征？
Something elemental...
某種常見...
...something terrifying.
...但是有可怕的東西
I assume that as you take on the underworld...
我要是沒理解錯的話...
...this symbol is a persona to protect those you care about from reprisals?
...你是要除暴安良？應該是 在危急時刻能夠解救民眾的象征
You're thinking about Rachel?
你的意思是保護雷切爾？
Actually, sir, I was thinking of myself.
實際上 我考慮的是我自己
Have you told anyone I'm coming back?
你告訴過別人我回來了嗎？
I couldn't figure the legal ramifications of bringing you back from the dead.
我還沒想清楚...怎麼樣恢復你這個在 法律上已經死亡者的身份
- Dead? - You've been gone seven years.
-已死亡者？ -你失蹤了七年
You had me declared dead?
你已經申請我死亡了？
Actually, it was Mr. Earle. He's taking the company public.
事實上是厄爾干的 他接管了公司
He wanted to liquidate your majority shareholding.
打算變賣你所佔有的大額股份
Those shares are worth quite a bit of money.
那可是一大筆錢呢
Well, it's a good thing I left everything to you, then.
幸虧當時我把一切都留給了你
Quite so, sir.
的確如此 先生
And you can borrow the Rolls, if you like. Just bring it back with a full tank.
你可以把那兩勞斯萊斯轎車借去開 回來時要加滿油
In my opinion, Mr. Zsaz is as much a danger to himself as to others...
在我看來 蔡司先生不僅對他人 而且對他自己都是一種威脅
...and prison is probably not the best environment for his rehabilitation.
而監獄的環境恐怕並不利於 他的治療和恢復
- Dr. Crane. - Miss Dawes.
-克蘭先生 -怎麼，道斯小姐
You think a man who butchers people for the mob doesn't belong in jail?
你真的認為像他這樣凶殘的殺手 不應該被送進監獄嗎？
I would hardly have testified to that otherwise, would I?
我可不會這麼說 你說呢 道斯小姐？
This is the third of Falcone's thugs you've had declared insane...
這已經是法爾科內的第三個殺手 經你證明精神失常...
...and moved into your asylum.
...而轉入你的精神病院的
The work offered by organized crime must have an attraction to the insane.
有組織的犯罪集團能夠提供的 工作可能對他們頗有吸引力
Or the corrupt.
對腐敗分子也一樣吧？
Mr. Finch.
芬奇先生
You should check with Miss Dawes here...
你應該過問一下道斯小姐身為檢察院的代表...
...just what implications your office has authorized her to make. If any.
...對我進行的影射和誣陷
- What are you doing? - What are you doing, Carl?
-怎麼回事 雷切爾小姐？ -怎麼回事 卡爾？
FINCH: Looking out for you.
芬奇:我在保護你呀
Falcone has half the city bought and paid for.
法爾科內把半個城市都收買了
- Drop it. - How can you say that?
-算了吧 -你怎麼能這麼說呢？
Because as much as I care about getting Falcone, I care more about you.
因為我越是了解法爾科內 我就越擔心的你安全
That's sweet.
說得真動聽
[SIRENS WAILING]
[警笛聲]
We've been through all that.
我們已經討論過這事啦
[BAT SQUEAKING]
[蝙蝠聲]
ALFRED: Blessed bat again, sir.
艾爾弗雷德:又一支蝙蝠
They nest somewhere in the grounds.
它們在庄園外面做了窩了
[BATS SQUEAKING]
[蝙蝠聲]
No more favors. Someone is sniffing around.
我不能再幫忙了 這事已經有人盯上了
Hey, I scratch your back, you scratch mine, doc.
嘿，互助友愛嗎 大夫
I'm bringing in the shipments.
我還幫你收貨呢
We are paying you for that.
我們是付錢的
Maybe money isn't as interesting to me as favors.
我對你幫忙比對錢更感興趣
I am more than aware that you are not intimidated by me, Mr. Falcone.
我並不視此為你對我的威脅 法爾科內先生
But you know who I'm working for, and when he gets here...
不過你也很清楚我為誰工作 等到他到達時...
He... He's coming to Gotham?
他要來哥特城？
Yes, he is.
是的
And when he gets here, he's not going to wanna hear...
當他來時 他一定不希望聽到...
...that you've endangered our operation just to get your thugs out of jail time.
...你為了讓你的小混混們少服刑 而置我們的計劃於危險之地
- Who's bothering you? - There's a girl at the DA's office.
-是誰讓你不安？ -市檢察院辦公室的一個姑娘家
- We'll buy her off. - Not this one.
-我們負責收買她 -她不吃這套
Idealist, huh?
一個理想主義者？嗯？
Well, there's an answer to that too.
我們也有對付這種人的辦法
- I don't want to know. - Yes, you do.
-我不想知道 -你應該知道
MAN: No, we are showing very healthy growth in these sectors.
不 我們這幾個部門的增長 十分良好
I don't think Thomas Wayne would have viewed heavy-arms manufacture...
我認為托馬斯.韋恩不會同意將武器生產...
...as a suitable cornerstone for our business.
...作為企業基礎產業的
Well, that's 20 years ago, Fredericks.
不錯，那是二十年前的事了 費德裡克
I think after 20 years we can allow ourselves...
我認為二十年後的今天 我們應該允許...
...to stop thinking about what Thomas Wayne would have done.
...不再以托馬斯.韋恩的意願為轉移了吧
JESSICA: Good morning, Mr. Earle's office.
杰西卡:早上好 厄爾先生辦公室
Yes, he's confirmed for the dinner tomorrow evening.
是的 他明天晚餐已經預訂了
BRUCE: Good morning. I'm here to see Mr. Earle.
布魯斯:早上好 我想見厄爾先生
Name?
您貴姓？
Bruce Wayne.
布魯斯.韋恩
Thomas would probably not have taken the company public.
托馬斯很可能也不同意 公司的股份上市
But that is what we, as responsible managers, are going to do.
但是這卻是我們這些 責任經營者打算做的事情
Jessica?
杰西卡？
Jessica? Where are you?
杰西卡？你在哪？
BRUCE: Eye on the ball, and... - Why is no one answering the phone?
布魯斯:眼睛盯著球，然後... -怎麼沒人接電話？
It's Wayne Enterprises, Mr. Earle. I'm sure they'll call back.
韋恩集團的電話，厄爾先生 我肯定他們還會再打過來的
Bruce? You're supposed to be dead.
布魯斯？你不是死了嗎？
I'm sorry to disappoint.
對不起讓你失望來了
- I need you to take a look at this. - Have you seen him yet?
-我希望你看看這個文件 -你見過他了嗎？
- Who? - Wayne.
-誰？ -韋恩
It's been all over the news. He's back.
這可是特大新聞 他回來了
EARLE: I'm sure you realize I can't stop the big machine.
厄爾:我已經無法阻止 這個龐大的機器了
Too many wheels turning.
太多的環節
- We're going public. - I understand.
-我們的股份就要上市了 -我明白
And I'll be handsomely rewarded for my shares.
而且我會得到豐厚的回報的
I'm not looking to interfere.
我來並不想干涉什麼
- I am looking for a job. - Oh?
-我隻是來找工作 -哦？
I just want to get to know the company that my family built.
我隻想了解一下 我家族的企業的情況
Any ideas where you would start?
你打算從哪兒開始呢？
Applied Sciences caught my eye.
我對產品開發部比較感興趣
Fox's department.
福克斯的部門？
I'll let him know you're coming.
我到時候通知他
You look like him. Your dad.
你長得很像他── 你的──父親
You're the only one left of the Wayne family.
你是韋恩家族唯一的一員了
This is where you belong. Welcome home.
你的根在這裡 歡迎回家
Environmental procedures, defense projects, consumer products.
環保程序 防御計劃 還有消費產品
All prototypes. None in production.
全都處於樣品階段
- On any level whatsoever. - None?
-沒有進入生產環節 -一個都沒有？
What did they tell you this place was?
他們怎麼向你介紹的？
BRUCE: They didn't tell me anything.
布魯斯:他們什麼都沒跟我說
Earle told me exactly what it was when he sent me down here.
厄爾當初派我來的時候 可是一字不差地這麼跟我說的
Dead end.
無所事事
Place to keep me from causing the board any more trouble.
派我來就是避免 我在董事會惹麻煩
Come on.
來吧
- You were on the board? - When your father ran things.
-你曾是董事會成員？ -你父親還在世的時候是
- You knew my father? - Oh, yeah.
-你認識我父親？ -是的
Helped him build his train.
我幫他造的火車
Here we are.
到了
Kevlar utility harness.
這是多功能防彈衣
Gas-powered, magnetic grapple gun.
強吸力抓鉤氣槍
The 350-pound test monofilament.
能夠承重350磅的單纖維
Wonderful project, your dad's train.
你父親的火車很棒
Routed it right into Wayne Tower, along with the water and power utilities.
直通韋恩大廈 水電公共設施到位
Kind of made Wayne Tower the unofficial center of Gotham City.
把韋恩大廈變成了 哥特城的民間中心
Of course, Earle let it go to rot. Here we are.
當然，厄爾後來毀了它
Nomex survival suit for advanced infantry.
這是諾邁司面料做的 步兵部隊阻燃軍服
Kevlar biweave, reinforced joints.
克福拉雙織沙面料
- Tear-resistant? - This sucker will stop a knife.
-耐撕扯？ -這東西連刀子都捅不破
- Bulletproof? - Anything but a straight shot.
-防彈嗎？ -除非是正面射擊
- Why didn't they put it into production? - Bean counters didn't think...
-為什麼不投入生產？ -預算部認為...
...a soldier's life was worth 300 grand.
...普通士兵的命不值300塊
So, what's your interest in it, Mr. Wayne?
那麼，你為什麼對這些感興趣呢？ 韋恩先生
I want to borrow it.
我想借用一下
For spelunking.
山洞探險
Spelunking?
山洞探險？
Yeah, you know, cave diving?
是的 就是鑽山洞
You expecting to run into much gunfire in these caves?
你借用這些盔甲 就為了鑽山洞嗎？
Look, I'd rather Mr. Earle didn't know about me borrowing...
我不希望厄爾先生知道 我借走了這些東西
Mr. Wayne...
韋恩先生...
...the way I see it...
...依我看...
...all this stuff is yours anyway.
...所有這些東西都屬於你的
Okay. Give it a try.
好吧，來試試吧
Charming.
太壯觀了
At least you'll have company.
至少你夢能做個伴
This must be the lowest foundation of the southeast wing.
這肯定是韋恩庄園東南地最低的地基
Your great-great-grandfather was involved in the Underground Railroad...
內戰期間你的曾曾祖父 卷入了地下交通組織...
...secretly transporting freed slaves to the North...
...秘密地把黑奴偷運到北方...
...and I suspect these caverns came in handy.
...我猜這些洞穴就是干這個用的
Alfred! Come up here!
艾爾弗雷德！快過來
I can see everything all right from down here, sir, thank you.
我在這看得很清楚 非常感謝，先生
ALFRED: We order the main part of this cowl from Singapore.
艾爾弗雷德:這頭罩的主要部分 是在新加坡定制的
BRUCE: Via a dummy corporation.
布魯斯:通過皮包公司？
Indeed. And then, quite separately...
就是 然後呢 我們又從...
...we place an order to a Chinese company for these.
...中國定制了這些東西 你看
- Put it together ourselves. - Precisely.
-我們再自己把他們拼裝起來？ -一點沒錯
They'll have to be large orders, to avoid suspicion.
因為訂購的量會很大 所以要避免疑心
- How large? - Say 10,000.
-有多大？ -我想大概十萬件
- Well, at least we'll have spares. - Yes.
-哦，還有好多剩下來 -就是
[SIRENS WAILING]
[警笛響]
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
[聽不到的耳語]
[WOMAN CHATTERING OVER POLICE RADIO]
[警察無線電裡女人的聲音]
Don't suppose you want a taste.
不想來點嗎？
I just keep offering, thinking maybe someday you'll get wise.
會一直源源不斷的 也許早晚有一天你會變聰明
There's nothing wise in what you do, Flass.
你這麼做一點都不聰明福拉斯
Well, Jimbo, you don't take the taste, makes us guys nervous.
不過 吉姆 你不參與 令我們非常緊張
I'm no rat.
我不是告密者
In a town this bent, who's there to rat to anyway?
再說了 在這個地方 我又能到哪兒去告密呢？
[LAUGHS]
[笑聲]
BATMAN: Don't turn around.
蝙蝠俠:別轉身
You're a good cop. One of the few.
你是個好警察 不多的幾個之一
GORDON: What do you want?
戈登:你想干什麼？
BATMAN: Carmine Falcone brings in shipments of drugs every week.
蝙蝠俠:卡曼.法爾科內每周都走私 成船的毒品進來
Nobody takes him down. Why?
可是為什麼沒人逮捕他
He's paid up with the right people.
他已經收買了當權者
What will it take to bring him down?
那怎樣才能制裁他？
Leverage on Judge Faden...
給法頓法官施壓...
...and a DA brave enough to prosecute.
...市檢察院有人敢提起公訴
Rachel Dawes.
雷切爾.道斯
Who are you?
你是誰？
BATMAN: Watch for my sign.
蝙蝠俠:認清我的標志
You're just one man?
就你一個嗎？
BATMAN: Now we're two.
蝙蝠俠:現在不是兩個？
We?
我們？
Freeze!
不許動
OFFICER: What the hell was that?
到底是什麼東西？
Just some nut.
不過是個瘋子
Well, what is it today? More spelunking?
今天想借什麼？ 還是去鑽山洞？
No. Today it's BASE-jumping.
不 去低空跳躍
BASE-jumping.
低空跳躍
- That like parachuting? - Kind of.
-就像跳傘一樣嗎？ -有點像
Do you have any lightweight fabrics?
你有那種分量很輕的面料嗎？
You know, I think I have just the thing.
正好 有這種東西
It's called memory cloth. Notice anything?
這叫做記憶面料 你聽說過嗎？
Regularly flexible...
正常情況下很柔軟..
...but put a current through it...
...一旦電流通過...
...molecules realign, it becomes rigid. - What kind of shapes can you make?
-...分子就會重組 他就會變得堅硬 -你能把它做成什麼形狀？
Can be tailored to fit any structure based on a rigid skeleton.
我能把它裁剪成任何形狀
Too expensive for the Army?
做軍服是不是太貴了?
I don't think they tried to market it to the billionaire, BASE-jumping crowd.
我想他們沒試過把它推銷給喜歡 鑽山洞和低空跳躍的億萬富翁
- Look, Mr. Fox. - Yes, sir?
-聽著 福克斯先生 -是的 先生
If you're uncomfortable...
要是你不願意的話--
Mr. Wayne, if you don't want to tell me exactly what you're doing...
韋恩先生 如果你不願意 告訴我實情的話...
...when I'm asked, I don't have to lie.
...那別人問我的時候 我也就用不著撒謊
But don't think of me as an idiot.
可是別把我當傻瓜
Fair enough.
著很合理
What's that?
那是什麼？
The Tumbler?
那個裝甲車？
Oh, you wouldn't be interested in that.
哦，你不會感興趣的
She was built as a bridging vehicle.
它是當臨時橋梁用的
During combat, two of these would jump over a river, towing cables.
在沖突中 兩輛轉向車 就可以越過河流 架起纜繩
Over here on the throttle, flip that open and throttle up.
你一碰這個開關就打開了 然後就整個的彈起來
This will boost you into a rampless jump... Not now!
遠遠的跳出去-- 不行 等會
Not... Not now, sir.
現在不要 先生
COMPUTER: Afterburner disengaged.
電腦:點火系統解除
We never could get the damn bridge to work...
橋梁試驗從來沒有成功過...
...but this baby works just fine.
...但是它彈跳得很好
So, what do you think?
你覺得怎麼樣？
Does it come in black?
有黑色的嗎？
I need you at the docks Thursday.
我要你到碼頭來 星期四
- Problems? - I don't want any trouble...
-有麻煩嗎？ -我希望最後一趟...
...with the last shipment. - Sure.
-...別出任何婁子 -當然
Word on the street is you got a beef with somebody in the DA's office.
據說市檢察院裡有人找你的麻煩
- Is that right? - And that there's a fat prize...
-是嗎？ -而且有一大筆錢...
...waiting for anybody willing to do anything about it.
...在等著有人處理此事呢
So, what's your point, Mr. Flass?
你想說什麼？福拉斯先生
Have you seen the girl?
你見過那女孩嗎？
FLASS [ON RADIO]: It's a cute little assistant D A.
福拉斯[無線電裡]: 一個嬌小可愛的檢察院助理
Don 't you think that's a little too much heat to bring down, maybe?
難道你不認為事情有些棘手嗎？
- Even for this town. - Never underestimate Gotham City.
-即使是在這樣的城市裡 -不要低軌哥特城
People get mugged coming home from work every day of the week.
每天上下班都有人被搶
Sometimes... Sometimes things just go bad.
有的時候-- 有的時候事情還會更嚴重一些
It's a problem with the graphite, sir.
這與石墨的含量有關
The next 10,000 will be up to specifications.
下一萬件會更結實些
- At least they gave us a discount. - Quite.
-至少這些價錢還打了折扣呢 -那倒是
In the meantime, sir, may I suggest you try to avoid landing on your head?
不過先生 我還是要提醒您 一定要避免頭部先著地
Why bats, Master Wayne?
為什麼選擇蝙蝠呢 韋恩少爺
Bats frighten me.
因為蝙蝠嚇著我
It's time my enemies shared my dread.
現在輪到敵人恐懼了
FLASS: What is this?
福拉斯:這是什麼？
Continue.
繼續干
Looks fine out there.
看著真不錯
The bears go straight to the dealers.
這些小熊直接送到毒販手裡
Yeah, and the rabbits go to the man in the Narrows.
是的 那些兔子是送給 住在窄島上的人的
- What's the difference? - Ignorance is bliss, my friend.
-有什麼區別嗎？ -你最好別打聽 我的朋友
Don't burden yourself with these secrets of scary people.
你千萬不要打聽 那些危險人物的秘密
[STEISS SCREAMS]
[叫喊聲]
Hey. Steiss.
嘿 斯泰斯？
Steiss?
斯泰斯？
MAN: What?
看什麼呢？
What the...?
怎麼會...
[SCREAMING IN DISTANCE]
[呼喊聲]
[GUNSHOTS]
[槍聲]
I better check it.
我去看看
[PANTING]
[喘息聲]
There's a problem out here. You better bail.
有麻煩了 你最好趕快走
[THUD]
[砰]
Where are you?!
你在哪兒？
Here.
在這
[SCREAMS]
[叫喊聲]
[GRUNTING]
[咕噥聲]
Take a ride. Oh, shit.
快開 該死
What the hell are you?
你到底是誰？
[GLASS SHATTERS]
[玻璃打碎聲]
I'm Batman.
我是蝙蝠俠
Nice coat.
外套不錯
Thanks.
謝謝
Hold it.
別動
That's right, you better run.
這就對了 你還是快跑吧
[SCREAMS]
[喊叫聲]
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
[電流沙沙聲]
Falcone sent them to kill you.
法爾科內派他們來殺你
- Why? - You rattled his cage.
-為什麼？ -因為你對他造成了威脅
- What's this? - Leverage.
-這是什麼？ -籌碼
- For what? - To get things moving.
-做什麼用？ -推動事態發展
Who are you?
你是誰？
Someone like you.
和你一樣的人
Someone who'll rattle the cages.
給他們造成威脅的人
Ma'am? Everything okay?
嘿 你沒事吧
OFFICER: Falcone's men? - Does it matter?
-法爾科內的人? -有什麼用？
We'll never tie him to it anyway.
能把他繩之以法麼？
I wouldn't be too sure of that.
我也沒辦法
What the hell is that?
那是什麼？
Cut him down.
給他鬆綁
LOEB: Unacceptable.
[哥特城郵報:蝙蝠教訓犯罪集團頭目] 雷波:決不允許
Now, I don't care if it's rival gangs, Guardian Angels...
我才不管他是什麼復仇小組 守護天使...
...or the goddamn Salvation Army...
...還是什麼救世軍...
...get them off the street and off the front page.
...統統把他們清掃出街道和報紙的頭條
They say it was just one guy. Or a creature.
據說隻有一個人或者說是某種生物
It was some asshole in a costume.
是個媽的穿戲服耍把戲的家伙
- Yeah? - This guy did deliver us...
-說吧 -可是這個穿戲服的家伙確實給我們...
...one of the city's biggest crime lords.
...送來了一個大毒梟
No one takes the law into their own hands in my city.
在我的城市裡 哪個人也無權擅自執法
Understand?
明白了嗎？
RACHEL: No way to bury it now. FINCH: There's still Judge Faden.
雷切爾:掩蓋不住了 芬奇:不過還有法頓法官
- I've got Faden covered. - What about this bat they babble about?
-我搞定法頓法官了 -可那個鬧得沸沸揚揚的蝙蝠怎麼辦？
Even if these guys will swear to being thrashed by a giant bat...
就算那些家伙說 被一個大蝙蝠襲擊了...
...we've got Falcone at the scene.
...可是我們還是在現場抓住了法爾科內
Drugs, prints, cargo manifests. This bat character gave us everything.
毒品 指紋 貨單 他把證據都給我們准備好了
Okay. Let's do it.
好吧 那咱們就干吧
- Bats are nocturnal. ALFRED: Bats may be.
-蝙蝠是夜行動物 艾爾弗雷德:不過即使是...
But even for billionaire playboys, 3:00 is pushing it.
身家億萬的花花公子 下午三點也不起床也太過分了
The price for leading a double life, I fear.
我擔心的是過雙重生活的代價
Your theatrics made an impression.
你的戲劇行動確實引人注意
BRUCE: Theatricality and deception...
布魯斯:戲劇性和出其不意...
...are powerful weapons, Alfred. This is a good start.
...確實是有力的武器 艾爾弗雷德 這是個良好的開端
If those are to be the first of many injuries to come...
如果這些傷痕隻是一系列傷痕的開始...
...it would be wise to find a suitable excuse.
...你最好找個聰明的借口
Polo, for instance.
比方說打馬球
I'm not learning polo, Alfred.
可我不會打馬球 艾爾弗雷德
Strange injuries, a nonexistent social life.
奇怪的創傷 一種不存在的社交生活
These things beg the question...
這會引起人們的興趣...
...as to what exactly does Bruce Wayne do with his time and his money.
...要琢磨布魯斯是 如何消磨他的時間和金錢的
What does someone like me do?
像我這樣的人通常會做什麼？
Drive sports cars, date movie stars.
開跑車 泡電影明星
Buy things that are not for sale.
買一些個非賣品
Who knows, Master Wayne, you start pretending to have fun...
這些事情 韋恩少爺 您就假裝您感興趣...
...you might even have a little by accident.
...也許某時你真的會感“性趣”
MAN: Sir.
先生
- We have a situation. - All right.
-我們有大麻煩了 -怎麼？
The Coast Guard picked up one of our cargo ships last night...
昨晚海安巡警找到了 我們的一隻貨船...
...heavily damaged, all crew missing, probably dead.
...已嚴重損毀 所有船員失蹤 估計已全部死亡
The ship was carrying a prototype weapon.
貨船運載了一批試驗武器
It's a microwave emitter.
是一種微波發射器
It's designed for desert warfare, but it...
是為了 --為了沙漠戰設計的--
It looks like somebody...
可是它好像被人...
...turned it on.
...給打開了
It uses focused microwaves to vaporize the enemy's water supply.
它是用來蒸發對手的供水設施的
The damage to the ship was catastrophic.
貨船損毀很嚴重
The weapon itself is...
而武器本身....
Missing?
也失蹤了
Yeah.
是
MAN: Mr. Wayne.
韋恩先生
Nice car.
真是好車
You should see my other one.
你應該見識見識我另一輛車
WOMAN: He's done something the police never have.
他干了警察干不了的事
MAN: You can't take the law into your own hands.
可也不改擅自執法
Well, at least he's getting something done.
話雖這麼說 但至少 他干了些他該干的事
MAN: Bruce, help me out here. - Huh?
-布魯斯 快幫我說句話吧 -嗯？
Well, a guy who dresses up like a bat clearly has issues.
哦 我認為 要是一個人 打扮成蝙蝠的模樣
But he's put Falcone behind bars.
肯定腦子有問題
MAN: Now the cops want him. What does that tell you?
可他到底把法爾科內關進了監獄 可現在警察卻要抓蝙蝠俠 這你怎麼看
They're jealous.
這是他們妒忌他
Sir, the pool is for decoration...
先生 噴水池隻是用來裝飾的...
...and your friends do not have swimwear.
...而且您的朋友沒穿泳衣
Well, they're European.
哦 他們是歐洲人 比較開放
I'm going to have to ask you to leave.
我不得不要求您離開
- It is not a question of money. - Well, you see...
-這不是錢的問題 -不過 嗯...
...I'm buying this hotel...
...我正在買下這個飯店...
...and setting some new rules about the pool area.
...而且我打算重新給 游泳區域定些新的規矩
I think the Batman deserves a medal.
我覺得應該給蝙蝠俠頒發勛章
And a straitjacket to pin it on.
應該給他穿上緊身衣
MAN: Thank you.
謝謝
Bruce?
布魯斯？
Rachel?
雷切爾？
I'd heard you were back.
我聽說你回來了
What are you doing?
你在干什麼呢？
Just swimming here. Wow, it is good to see you.
在這游泳 哦 很高興再見面
You were gone a long time.
你走了很長時間
- I know. How are things? - The same.
-我知道 你怎麼樣？ -老樣子
Job's getting worse.
工作越來越不好做了
Can't change the world on your own.
一個人的力量是無法改變世界的
What choice do I have...
我還能有有什麼其它的選擇...
...when you're too busy swimming?
...連你都在忙著游泳
Rachel, all of...
雷切爾 這些--
All this...
所有這些....
It's... It's not me. It's...
-- 都不是我 其實 我....
Inside, I am...
內心 ...
I am more.
有苦衷
WOMAN 1: Come on, Bruce. Come on.
來 布魯斯 快點
WOMAN 2: Bruce, we have some more hotels for you to buy.
布魯斯 來 我們還要去買下更多的飯店
Bruce...
布魯斯...
...deep down you may still be that same great kid you used to be.
...也許你仍然是那個出色的男孩
But it's not who you are underneath...
但是這不是你過去如何的問題...
...it's what you do that defines you.
...重要的是你現在的表現
WOMAN: Dr. Crane, thanks for coming.
謝謝你能來 克蘭醫生
Not at all. He cut his wrists?
別客氣 他割脈了？
Probably looking for the insanity plea. But if anything should happen...
也許是為了保外就醫 但一旦發生任何意外的話...
Of course, better safe than sorry.
那當然 安全第一
Yeah, Dr. Crane, I can't take it anymore. It's all too much.
啊 克蘭醫生 我再也受不了了 太可怕了
The walls are closing in. Blah, blah, blah.
四面的牆壁像我壓呀 壓呀 壓過來
A couple of days of this food, it'll be true.
吃了好幾天這種伙食 我不瘋才怪呢
- What do you want? - I wanna know...
-你現在想怎麼辦？ -我現在想知道...
...how you're gonna convince me to keep my mouth shut.
...你到底打算怎樣讓我保持沉默
About what? You don't know anything.
為什麼事呢？ 你什麼也不知道
I know you don't want the cops to take a closer look at the drugs they seized.
我知道你不想讓警察過多地了解 他們起獲的那些毒品
And I know about your experiments with the inmates of your nut house.
我還知道你在你的精神病院裡 用病人作的那些藥物試驗
See, I don't go into business with a guy without finding out his dirty secrets.
你瞧 我從不跟 我不了解背景的人合作
And those goons you used.
還有你雇用的那些打手
I own the muscle in this town.
我掌握著這座城市所有的罪犯
Now, I've been bringing your stuff in for months...
目前 我已經幫你 走私藥品好幾個月了...
...so whatever he's planning, it's big, and I want in.
...不管你的老板在計劃什麼 反正是樁大買賣 而我要加入
Well, I already know what he'll say.
那麼 你就知道他要說什麼啦
That we should kill you.
我們應該干掉你
Even he can't get me in here. Not in my town.
就是他也不能把我怎麼樣 至少在這不能
Would you like to see my mask?
你想看看我的面罩嗎？
I use it in my experiments.
我用來做藥物試驗的
Now, I'm probably not very frightening to a guy like you.
對你這樣的人恐怕並不怎麼可怕
But these crazies, they can't stand it.
不過我想對那些警察 他們受不了這種瘋狂
So when did the nut take over the nut house?
那麼那些家伙是什麼表現?
[SCREAMING]
[叫喊聲]
SCARECROW: They scream and they cry...
稻草人:他們又哭又叫的...
...much as you're doing now.
...就像你現在這樣
Well, he's not faking. Not that one.
看來 他並不是假裝的
I'll talk to the judge and see if I can get him moved...
我得去跟法官談談 看我是否可以把他...
...to the secure wing at Arkham. I can't treat him here.
...帶回阿克漢姆 在這裡我無法給他治療
BATMAN: Storm's coming.
蝙蝠俠:暴風雨就要來了
The scum is getting jumpy because you stood up to Falcone.
你打敗了法爾科內 把警長氣瘋啦
It's a start. Your partner was at the docks with Falcone.
這剛開個頭 你的搭檔當時也在碼頭
Well, he moonlights as a low-level enforcer.
不錯 他的第二職業 是充當個小打手
They were splitting the shipment in two. Only half went to the dealers.
他們把貨物分成兩份 隻有一半是給毒販子的
Why? What about the other half?
為什麼？那另一半呢？
- Flass knows. - He won't talk.
-福拉斯知道 -他不會說的
He'll talk to me.
他會跟我說的
GORDON: Commissioner Loeb set up a massive task force to catch you.
戈登: 雷波特派員 組織了大量的警力要抓捕你
- He thinks you're dangerous. - What do you think?
-他認為你很危險 那你怎麼認為呢？
I think you're trying to help.
我認為你再給我們提供幫助
But I've been wrong before.
我以前誤解你了
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[雷聲]
[SIRENS WAILING]
[警笛聲]
FLASS: Come on, I ain't got all night.
福拉斯:快點 快點
Flass, I have kids to feed.
福拉斯  我還要養活孩子呢
What, they don't like falafel?
怎麼 他們不喜歡三明治嗎？
[SCREAMING]
[喊叫聲]
Where were the other drugs going?
另外那些毒品送到哪兒去了？
I never knew. I don't know.
我根本就不知道 我不知道
- I swear to God. - Swear to me!
-我向上帝發誓 我不知道 -還是向我發誓吧
[SCREAMING]
[喊叫聲]
I don't... I don't know. I never knew. Never.
我不 -- 我不知道 我根本就不知道 真的
They went to some guy for a couple days before they went to the dealers.
他們先送到某人那裡放幾天 然後再送給毒販子
Why?
為什麼？
There was something... Something else in the drugs...
那裡面　有些其他的東西...
...something hidden. - What?
-...別人不知道的東西 -什麼東西？
I never went to the drop-off point. It was in the Narrows.
我從來沒去過最終的送貨地點 是在窄島
- Cops only go there in force. - Do I look like a cop?
-警察不敢單個進入那個地區 -我像警察嗎？
No...!
不要--!
FINCH: This is the one I'm talking about.
芬奇:我說的就是這個
- What's your problem with it? - It shouldn't exist.
-什麼事？ -它不應該在這裡
This ship left Singapore with 246 containers, but arrived with 247.
這個貨船離開新加坡時承載的是 ２６６噸的貨櫃
I'm guessing there's something I'm not supposed to find in there.
而現在是２６７噸 這裡邊肯定有問題啊
Listen, counselor, we don't wanna know what's in Mr. Falcone's crate.
聽著　長官　我們從來不打聽 法爾科內先生都運了些什麼貨
Things are working a little differently now. Open it up.
現在變了　把它打開
FINCH: What the hell is this?
芬奇:這他媽的是什麼？
[GUNSHOTS]
[槍聲]
It's you, isn't it? Everybody's been talking about you.
就是你　對不對 大家都在談論你
MAN: Get in here!
快進來
The other kids won't believe me.
他們肯定不相信
[DOOR OPENS]
[開門聲]
Get rid of all traces.
銷毀所有痕跡
MAN: Better torch the whole place. CRANE: All right.
那還不如燒掉 克蘭:也好
[GLASS SHATTERS]
[玻璃破碎聲]
SCARECROW: Having trouble?
稻草人:怎麼　有問題嗎？
Take a seat. Have a drink.
坐吧　喝點水
You look like a man who takes himself too seriously.
看來你太自以為是了
Do you want my opinion? You need to lighten up.
想聽我的建議嗎？ 你需要放鬆一下
[GROANING]
[呻吟聲]
Alfred, help me.
艾爾弗雷德　來幫忙
Blood. Take. Take poison. Blood poison.
放血　有毒　放血　有毒
Poisonous. Poisonous.
有毒　有毒
THOMAS: Bruce...
托馬斯:布魯斯...
...why do we fall?
...怎麼掉下去的？
- How long was I out? - Two days.
-我昏迷了多久？ -兩天
It's your birthday.
今天是你的生日
Many happy returns.
生日快樂轉運
I've felt these effects before, but this was so much more potent.
我以前有過這種反應 不過這次更強烈
It was some kind of hallucinogen, weaponized, in aerosol form.
像是一種氣霧致幻化學武器
You have been hanging out in the wrong clubs, Mr. Wayne.
你進錯俱樂部了吧　韋恩先生
I called Mr. Fox when your condition worsened after the first day.
頭一天情況不太好 所以我把福克斯先生叫來了
FOX: I analyzed your blood...
福克斯:我給你做了血檢...
...isolating the receptor compounds and the protein-based catalyst.
...分離受體化合物 以及蛋白基催化物
Am I meant to understand any of that?
我有必要懂這些專業術語嗎？
Not at all. I just wanted you to know how hard it was.
不必要　我隻想讓你 明白這有多復雜
- Bottom line, I synthesized an antidote. - Could you make more?
-總之　我合成了一種解毒藥 -你能在多做些嗎？
You planning on gassing yourself again, Mr. Wayne?
你想再過過癮嗎？　韋恩先生
Well, you know how it is. You're out at night, looking for kicks...
我說　你知道怎麼回事 晚上出去打架的時候...
...someone's passing around the weaponized hallucinogens...
...說不定又被人用迷幻藥下暗手...
I'll bring what I have. The antidote should inoculate you for now.
我把剩下的拿來 已經注射的解毒劑已經起效了
Alfred, always a pleasure.
艾爾弗雷德　很高興見到你
Lucius.
盧修斯
- You sure you don't want to come in? - I have to get back.
-真的不進來嗎？ -我得回去了
- I wanted to leave this. - Thank you.
-我隻想把這個留下 -謝謝你
BRUCE: Rachel?
布魯斯:雷切爾？
RACHEL: Looks like someone's been burning the candle at both ends.
雷切爾:看來有人在連軸轉哪
- Must've been quite an occasion. - It is my birthday.
-你是不是很累呀？ -我過生日
I know. I'm sorry I can't come tonight. I was just dropping off your present.
我知道 抱歉我今晚來不了了 我隻是把禮物送過來
- You've got better plans? - My boss has been missing for days...
-晚上有更好的安排嗎？ -我的上司失蹤兩天了...
...which means I should probably start by looking...
...這種情況就意味著我應該...
...at the bottom of the river. - Rachel.
-...去河裡打撈他 -雷切爾.
[CELL PHONE RINGS]
[手機響]
RACHEL: Excuse me.
-雷切爾 -不好意思
Rachel Dawes.
雷切爾.道斯
Who authorized that? Get Crane down there now. Don't take no for an answer.
誰給他這權力 把克蘭馬上帶到辦公室 不許他說不
Call Dr. Lehmann, tell him we need our own assessment to the judge by morning.
給萊曼醫生打電話 告訴他明天一早 把自己的評估報告放在法官的辦公桌上
- What's wrong? - It's Falcone.
-出什麼事了？ -是法爾科內.
Dr. Crane moved him to Arkham Asylum on suicide watch.
克蘭醫生把他帶到 阿克漢姆精神病院去了
You're going to Arkham now? It's in the Narrows, Rachel.
你現在要去阿克漢姆嗎？ 那可是在窄島上呀 雷切爾
You enjoy your party, Bruce.
你過你的生日吧 布魯斯
- Some of us have work to do. - You be careful.
-我們可有工作要做了 -多加小心
Happy birthday.
-生日快樂 紙條書
But, Master Wayne, the guests will be arriving.
但是 韋恩少爺 客人們馬上就要到了
Keep them happy until I arrive.
我回來之前 想辦法讓他們高興
Tell them that joke you know.
把你知道的笑話講給他們聽
[PLAYING PIANO]
[鋼琴聲]
EARLE: Having fun?
厄爾:玩得挺高興嗎？
Bill? Now, what's a big shot like you doing in a place like this?
厄爾？你這個大人物 來這種地方干什麼？
I need some information.
我想知道些資料
The Wayne Enterprise 47-B, 1 -ME.
韋恩企業產品47-B 1-ME.
1 -ME.
1-ME.
It's a microwave emitter. It was designed to vaporize an enemy's water supply.
是微波發射器 設計的目的是為了蒸發敵人的供水系統
Rumor was they tested dispersing water-based chemicals into the air...
據說他們曾經用親水化學介質作測試...
...but isn't that illegal?
...可這樣做是不是違法的？
I want all the information on the development of this project...
我需要所有這個研發項目的...
...all data, files, backup disks, on my desk right away.
...所有數據 檔案和背景資料
Did you lose one?
都說全了？
I'm merging your department with Archives.
我把你的部門合並到檔案部
And I am firing you.
同時 我把你解雇了
Didn't you get the memo?
你看見我給你的備忘錄嗎？
FALCONE: Scarecrow.
法爾科內:稻草人
Scarecrow.
稻草人
Miss Dawes, this is most irregular.
道斯小姐 這很反常
I have nothing to add to the report I filed with the judge.
我對已經交給法官的報告 沒有任何補充了
- I have questions about your report. - Such as?
-我對你的報告有疑問 -舉個例子
Isn't it convenient for a 52-year-old man who has no history of mental illness...
對於一個52歲從無精神病史的男人來說...
...to have a psychotic breakdown just when he's about to be indicted?
...在被起訴的時候突然之間精神崩潰 這也太不說得過去了吧
As you can see for yourself, there is nothing convenient about his symptoms.
是啊 正如你自己親眼所見 他的症狀實在是太說不過去了
- Scarecrow. - What's "scarecrow"?
-稻草人. -什麼"稻草人 "?.
Patients suffering delusional episodes often focus their paranoia...
病人通常會被某種幻覺所控制...
...on an external tormentor...
...外在表現痛苦...
...usually one conforming to Jungian archetypes.
...通常會寄托一種原型
In this case, a scarecrow.
而在他身上，就是稻草人
- He's drugged? - Psychopharmacology is my primary field.
-他服藥了嗎？ -精神病藥理學是我的第一專業
CRANE [ON RADIO]: I'm a strong advocate.
克蘭 [無線電上] : 我是藥物的堅決擁護者
Outside, he was a giant.
在外邊他是強人
In here, only the mind can grant you power.
在這裡 隻有意識才是強者
You enjoy the reversal.
你更願意顛倒過來
I respect the mind's power over the body.
我更推崇意識超過生理
It's why I do what I do.
這也使我選擇我的工作的原因
I do what I do to keep thugs like Falcone behind bars, not in therapy.
我選擇的工作就是把法爾科內 這樣的惡棍關進監獄 而不是精神病院
I want my own psychiatric consultant to have full access to Falcone...
我需要我們自己的精神病學醫生 對法爾科內做更全面的檢查...
...including blood work. Find out what exactly you put him on.
..包括他的血液 查出你給他用了什麼藥
- First thing tomorrow, then. - Tonight.
-明天一早再說 -就今晚
I've already paged Dr. Lehmann at County General.
我已經通知康提總院的萊曼醫生了
CRANE: As you wish.
克蘭:隨你的便吧
This way, please.
這邊請
There's something I think you should see.
有些東西你應該看一看
This is where we make the medicine.
這裡是我們制藥的地方
Perhaps you should have some, clear your head.
也許你應該來點 給你醒醒腦
[SCREAMING]
[喊叫聲]
Who knows you're here?
有誰知道你來這？
Who knows?
誰知道？
He's here.
他來了
MAN 1: Who?
誰？
The Batman.
蝙蝠俠
MAN 1: What do we do? - What anyone does...
咱們怎麼辦？ -發現小偷後...
...when a prowler comes around.
...一般人都怎麼辦？
- Call the police. - You want the cops here?
-報警 -你想把警察招來？
At this point, they can't stop us.
現在他們不能阻止我們
But the Batman has a talent for disruption.
但是蝙蝠俠老喜歡搗亂
Force him outside, the police will take him down. Go.
我們把他逼到外面去 警察自然會逮住他 走
MAN 1: What about her? CRANE: She hasn't got long.
他怎麼辦？ 克蘭:她堅持不了多久
I gave her a concentrated dose.
我給了他超濃縮的劑量
The mind can only take so much. Now go.
意識再強也撐不了多久 現在走吧
MAN 2: The things they say about him.
他們傳說的是真的嗎？
Can he really fly?
他真會飛嗎？
MAN 3: I heard he can disappear.
我聽說他會隱身
Well, we'll find out.
好吧 咱們這就會知道的
Won't we?
對不對？
[GUNSHOTS]
[槍聲]
Taste of your own medicine, doctor?
嘗嘗自己的藥吧 醫生
What have you been doing here?
你都在這搞了什麼鬼？
Who are you working for?
你在為誰工作？
Ra's... Ra's al Ghul.
拉 -- 拉.阿勒古爾
Ra's al Ghul is dead. Who are you working for?
拉.阿勒古爾已經死了 到底為誰工作？
Crane.
克蘭
Dr. Crane isn't here right now.
克蘭醫生現在不在
But if you'd like to make an appointment...
如果你願意約定的話....
[SIRENS WAILING]
[警笛聲]
OFFICER [OVER P.A.]: Batman, put down your weapons and surrender.
蝙蝠俠 放下武器 出來投降
You're surrounded.
你被包圍了
- What are you waiting for? - Backup.
-你們還等什麼呢？ -等後援
- Backup? - The Batman's in there.
-後援？ -蝙蝠俠在裡面
SWAT's on the way. But if you wanna go in now...
SWAT馬上就要到了...
...I'll be right behind you, sir.
...你要是進去我會跟著你的 先生
SWAT's on the way.
SWAT已經出發了
- Hey. - Hey.
-嘿 -嘿
GORDON: What's happened to her?
戈登:她怎麼了？
Crane poisoned her with a psychotropic hallucinogen, a panic-inducing toxin.
克蘭給她噴了一種毒藥 能引起恐懼的致幻劑
- Let me get her down to the medics. - They can't help her, but I can.
-我帶她去急救 -他們救不了他，我能
Get her downstairs. Meet me in the alley.
帶她下樓 在後巷裡等我
Crane's been smuggling his toxin hidden in Falcone's drugs...
克蘭把致毒劑需要的化學品 藏在法爾科內的貨裡偷運進來...
...and they're dumping it into the water supply.
...打算投在城市的供水系統裡
- What was he planning? - I don't know.
-他到底想干什麼？ -我不清楚
Was he working for Falcone?
他為法爾科內工作嗎？
He mentioned someone else, someone worse.
他提到了另一個人 一個更惡的人
She needs the antidote before the damage is permanent.
我要趕在毒劑對她 造成永久傷害前給她解毒
- How long does she have? - Not long.
-她還能堅持多久？ -沒多久了
[BUZZING IN DISTANCE]
[嗡嗡聲]
What is that?
什麼聲音？
- Backup. - What the...?
-援軍到了 -這是什麼？
[BATS SQUEAKING]
[蝙蝠嘯叫聲]
Excuse me.
打攪了
BATMAN: How is she? - She's fading. We gotta go.
蝙蝠俠:她怎麼樣？ -暈過去了 咱們得趕快走
I'll get my car.
我去開車
BATMAN: I brought mine.
蝙蝠俠:我有開車來
Yours?
你的車？
I've gotta get me one of those.
我也要弄一輛這樣的
OFFICER 1: He is in a vehicle.
他上了一輛交通工具
OFFICER 2 [OVER RADIO]: Make and color?
車？什麼顏色？
It's a black...
一輛黑色的...
...tank.
...坦克
Stay calm.
鎮靜
You've been poisoned.
你中毒了
I'm on him.
我跟著他
Breathe slowly.
穩住呼吸
Hold on.
坐穩了
- What are you doing? - Shortcut.
-你在干什麼 -抄近路
OFFICER 3 [OVER RADIO]: Air One to ground, block that ramp.
[無線電]:空中呼叫地面 他被堵住了
He's got no way off that roof.
他在房頂沒地跑了
Turn off your engine. Step away from the car.
關閉發動機 從車上下來
- Trust me. COMPUTER: Weapons system activated.
-相信我 電腦:武器系統就緒
Who is this guy?
這家伙是誰？
OFFICER 2 [OVER RADIO]: Where's he going?
[無線電]:他往哪去啦？
He's on the roof.
他在屋頂上
OFFICER 2: What street is he taking? - He's not on a street.
-他走到哪條街？ -他不是在街上
He's flying on rooftops.
他在屋頂上飛呢
At least tell me what it looks like.
至少告訴我那車什麼樣？
Never mind.
不用了
Got him.
我看見它了
Coming right up on his butt.
我們追上他了
OFFICER 3: We're tracking suspect vehicle heading west on l- 17.
我們在I-17大道向西追蹤可疑車輛
- Air One to ground. - I lost him.
-空中一號呼叫地面 -丟失目標
OFFICER 3: We've lost visual. Exit 9 is blocked.
我們失去目標 9號出口已封鎖
We'll loop back to check the frontage road.
我們掉頭再去搜尋其它街道
COMPUTER: Stealth mode activated.
電腦:潛行功能開啟
Stay with me.
堅持住
What...? There he is.
什麼？它在那
Just hold on.
千萬堅持住
Rachel!
雷切爾!
GORDON: They get any of this into the mains?
給韋恩少爺 福克斯送
OFFICER: Yeah.
戈登:他們把這些毒劑 投放到供水系統沒有？
Notify the water company. There's gotta be a way to isolate it.
投了
No. They put it all in. They must've been at this for weeks.
通知自來水公司 隔離那些還沒有投放的區域
- Gotham's entire water supply is laced. - Why haven't we felt the effects?
他們在所有地點都投放了 肯定已經持續了好幾個星期了
Must be a compound that has to be absorbed through the lungs.
-哥特的供水系統都已經被污染了 -為什麼我們沒有反應？
[BATS SQUEAKING]
一定要進入呼吸道才有作用
BATMAN: How do you feel?
[蝙蝠嘯叫聲]
Where are we?
蝙蝠俠:你感覺如何？
- Why did you bring me here? - lf I hadn't, your mind would be lost.
我們這是在哪？
- You were poisoned. - It was...
-怎麼把我帶到這來？ -我要不這麼做你就喪失意識了
- It was Dr. Crane. - Rest. Gordon has Crane.
-你中毒了 -是--
Is Sergeant Gordon your friend?
-是克蘭醫生 -放心吧，戈登已經抓住了克蘭
I don't have the luxury of friends.
戈登警官是你的朋友嘛？
I'm gonna give you a sedative. You'll wake up back at home.
擁有朋友對我來說太奢侈了
When you do, get these to Gordon, and Gordon alone. Trust no one.
我給你注射鎮靜劑 等你醒來時就在自己家裡了
- What are they? - The antidote.
你把這些交給戈登 親自交給 他本人 不要相信任何人
One for Gordon to inoculate himself, the other for mass production.
-是什麼？ -是抗體
RACHEL: Mass production?
一份給戈登 其它的用來大量生產
Crane was just a pawn. We need to be ready.
雷切爾:大量生產
When you told me your grand plan for saving Gotham...
克蘭不過是個小卒 我們必須做好准備
...all that stopped me from calling the men in white coats...
當你跟我說要拯救哥特城的時候...
...was when you said it wasn't about thrill-seeking.
...我之所以沒有叫穿白大褂的人...
- It's not. - What would you call that?
...就是因為你說了一句話 說你這不是尋找刺激
- Damn good television. - It's a miracle no one was killed.
-確實不是 -那你把這叫什麼？
I didn't have time to observe the rules of the road, Alfred.
-該死的電視 -居然無人受傷 真是奇跡
You're getting lost inside this monster of yours.
我當時沒時間遵守交規了 艾爾弗雷德
I'm using this monster to help other people, just like my father did.
你已經被你內心的野獸沖昏了頭
For Thomas Wayne, helping others...
我在利用這支野獸幫助其它的人 就像我父親當年做的一樣
...wasn't about proving anything to anyone, including himself.
對於托馬斯.韋恩來說 幫助其它人...
It's Rachel, Alfred. She was dying.
...並不意味著向別人證明什麼 包括他自己
She's downstairs, sedated. I need you to take her home.
是為了雷切爾 艾爾弗雷德 她當時要死了
Well, we both care for Rachel, but what you're doing has to be beyond that.
現在她在樓下 注射了鎮靜劑 你送她回家吧
It can't be personal, or you're just a vigilante.
我們都關心雷切爾 可你做的已經超越了這一點
- Is Fox still here? - Yes, sir.
不是針對她一個人 或者你就是個義務警員
We need to send these people away.
-福克斯在嗎？ -在 先生
Those are Bruce Wayne's guests. You have a name to maintain.
咱們該把那些客人送走了
I don't care about my name.
那些可都是布魯斯.韋恩的朋友 你要注意名聲
It's not just your name, sir. It's your father's name.
我才不在乎名聲呢
And it's all that's left of him.
不止是你的名聲 還有您父親的
Don't destroy it.
這是他留下的一切
[GUESTS SINGING "HAPPY BIRTHDAY"]
不要毀了他
- Mr. Earle. - Happy birthday, Bruce.
[客人們唱生日歌]
Thank you.
-厄爾先生 -生日快樂 布魯斯.
How did the stock offering go?
謝謝
Prices soared.
股票上市情況如何？
Who was buying?
市值相當高
All kinds of funds and brokerages.
誰在買？
It's a bit technical.
各種基金會和經紀公司
The key thing is...
這麼說技術上有點難懂
...our company's future is secure.
總而言之...
Great.
...我們企業的未來是有保障的了
A little the worse for wear, I'm afraid.
太棒了
GORDON: What was the plan, Crane?
沒事的 她喝多了
How were you gonna get your toxin into the air?
戈登:計劃到底是什麼？克蘭？
Scarecrow. Scarecrow.
你打算怎樣把你的毒劑 釋放到空氣中
Who were you working for, Crane?
稻草人. 稻草人.
Oh, it's too late.
你在為誰工作 克蘭？
You can't stop it now.
已經太晚了
GORDON: Here.
你已經無法阻止這一切
MAN: Happy birthday, Bruce. - Thank you. Thanks.
戈登:過來
And thank you for that item.
生日快樂 布魯斯. -謝謝你 謝謝
You're welcome.
還有你送我的那些東西
- I know you'll put it to good use. - I already have.
別客氣
How long would it take to manufacture on a large scale?
-我知道你會好好利用它的 -已經好好利用了
Weeks. Why?
大規模生產的話需要多長時間？
Somebody's planning to disperse the toxin using the water supply.
幾個星期 怎麼了？
The water supply won't help you disperse an inhalant.
有人打算利用供水系統 大范圍投放致幻劑
What?
這樣做無法感染呼吸系統
Unless you have a microwave emitter powerful enough...
什麼？
...to vaporize all the water in the mains.
除非使用大功率的微波蒸發器...
A microwave emitter like the one Wayne Enterprises just misplaced.
...是被污染的水全部蒸發
Misplaced?
就像韋恩企業剛剛失竊的那種微波蒸發器一樣
Earle just fired me for asking too many questions about it.
失竊的？
Go back to Wayne Enterprises now and start making more of that antidote.
厄爾開除了我 就是因為我問的問題多
The police are gonna need as much as they can get their hands on.
我需要你立即返回韋恩企業 開始生產盡可能多的解毒劑
My security clearance has been revoked.
我認為警察很快就會有 大量的需求的
That wouldn't stop a man like you, would it?
我的出入證已經被吊銷了
I suppose not.
我認為這點事難不到你吧？
- Bruce, there's somebody you must meet. - Not now, Mrs. Delane.
應該是吧
Now, am I pronouncing this right...
-布魯斯 有個人想見見你 你有時間嗎？ -現在不行 德林夫人
...Mr. Ra's al Ghul?
那麼 我的念法對嗎？...
You're not Ra's al Ghul.
...拉.阿勒古爾先生
I watched him die.
你不是拉.阿勒古爾
DUCARD: But is Ra's al Ghul immortal?
我親眼看見他死的
Are his methods supernatural?
杜卡德:可拉.阿勒古爾不是不朽的嗎？
Or cheap parlor tricks to conceal your true identity, Ra's?
他的意念不是超越現實的嗎？
Surely a man who spends his nights scrambling over the rooftops of Gotham...
或者簡單的易容術就能隱藏起 你的真實面目把 杜卡德
...wouldn't begrudge me dual identities.
當然了 一個半夜裡到處爬屋頂的人...
I saved your life.
...恐怕不會抱怨我的雙重身份吧？
I warned you about compassion, Bruce.
我救了你的命
Your quarrel is with me.
我提醒過你不能憐憫 布魯斯
You let these people go.
你是沖著我來的吧？
You are welcome to explain the situation to them.
讓這些客人走吧
BRUCE: Everyone.
那就麻煩你給他們解釋一下吧
Everybody?
布魯斯:諸位
I...
諸位
I want to thank you all for coming here tonight and drinking all of my booze.
我...
[GUESTS LAUGHING]
我很感謝大家今晚能 出席我的生日宴會喝光了我的酒
No, really.
[笑聲]
There's a thing about being a Wayne...
不 真的
...that you're never short of a few freeloaders, like yourselves...
作為韋恩家族的一員我知道...
...to fill up your mansion with. So here's to you people. Thank you.
...身邊少不了騙吃騙喝的人，就像你們...
- That's enough, Bruce. - I'm not finished.
...也隻是為了撐場面湊人數 為了諸位干杯 謝謝你們
To all of you...
-太過分了 布魯斯. -我還沒說完
All of you phonies, all of you two-faced friends...
為你們這些....
...you sycophantic suck-ups who smile through your teeth at me...
所有這些虛偽的家伙 所有這些兩面三刀的朋友...
...please, leave me in peace.
...所有這些阿諛奉承之人 以及勢力的小人們...
Please go.
...請你們讓我清靜清靜吧
Stop smiling, it's not a joke. Please leave.
請你們走吧
The party's over, get out.
收起你們的假笑吧 我並不是開玩笑 請大家離開吧
The apple has fallen very far from the tree, Mr. Wayne.
宴會結束了 現在滾吧
He's turning into a jerk.
韋恩先生 你與你的 父母真是天壤之別
Amusing.
他怎麼變得這麼古怪了
But pointless. None of these people have long to live.
有意思
Your antics at the asylum have forced my hand.
但是無濟於事 這些人都活不長了
So Crane was working for you.
你的解毒藥迫使我提前出手
His toxin is derived from the organic compound found in our blue flowers.
這麼說克蘭是為你工作
He was able to weaponize it.
他的致幻劑是從我們的 藍色花朵裡提煉出來的
He's not a member of the League of Shadows?
他把它制成了武器
Of course not. He thought our plan was to hold the city to ransom.
他並不是影子同盟的成員
But really, you are gonna release Crane's poison on the entire city.
當然不是 他以為我們要用致幻劑要挾政府呢
Then watch Gotham tear itself apart through fear.
可你打算用克蘭的毒劑污染整個城市
BRUCE: You're gonna destroy millions of lives.
然後欣賞整個哥特城陷入恐懼和毀滅的景象
DUCARD: Only a cynical man would call what these people have "lives," Wayne.
布魯斯:你要毀掉幾百萬人的生命
Crime. Despair.
杜卡德:隻有瘋子才把這些人的生命當回事 韋恩
This is not how man was supposed to live.
罪惡 絕望
The League of Shadows has been a check against human corruption...
人類的生活不該是這個樣
...for thousands of years.
影子同盟致力於緝查人類的腐敗...
We sacked Rome. Loaded trade ships with plague rats.
...已歷經千年
Burned London to the ground.
我們毀滅了羅馬 貨船把鼠疫帶到了世界各個角落
Every time a civilization reaches the pinnacle of its decadence...
還把倫敦燒成了殘垣斷壁
...we return to restore the balance.
每一次文明一旦陷入腐敗的泥沼...
Gotham isn't beyond saving.
...我們就會出來維持平衡
Give me more time. There are good people here.
哥特城還沒有淪落到 不可救藥的地步
You're defending a city so corrupt...
給我點時間 這裡還有不少好人
...we have infiltrated every level of its infrastructure.
你要保護的城市...
Time to play.
...我們已經滲透到社會的每一個階層
When I found you in that jail, you were lost.
游戲時間到了
But I believed in you.
我在監獄裡見到你的時候 你很迷失低落
I took away your fear, and I showed you a path.
但是現在 我恢復了對你的信心
You were my greatest student.
我消除了你的恐懼 給你指明了出路
It should be you standing by my side, saving the world.
你是我的得意門生
I'll be standing where I belong.
你應該站在我這一邊 拯救世界
Between you and the people of Gotham.
我將站在我該屬於的一方
No one can save Gotham.
站在你和哥特城人們中間
When a forest grows too wild, a purging fire is inevitable and natural.
誰也救不了哥特城
Tomorrow the world will watch in horror as its greatest city destroys itself.
當森林生長得過於茂盛的時候 一場大火的降臨是再自然不過的
The movement back to harmony will be unstoppable this time.
明天 世界將共同矚目 這個偉大的城市自己毀滅自己
- You attacked Gotham before? - Of course.
平衡的運動是不可阻擋的
Over the ages our weapons have grown more sophisticated.
-以前你襲擊過哥特城嗎？ -當然
With Gotham we tried a new one. Economics.
經過長時間的發展 我們的武器越來越先進
But we underestimated certain of Gotham's citizens...
在哥特城 我們採用 一種新型武器 經濟
...such as your parents.
但是我卻低估了哥特城的一些市民...
Gunned down by one of the very people they were trying to help.
...比如你的父母
Create enough hunger and everyone becomes a criminal.
結果他們被他們一心要救助的人槍殺了
Their deaths galvanized the city into saving itself...
無處不在的飢餓使人人變成了罪犯
...and Gotham has limped on ever since.
他們的死摧毀了這個城市的自救之心...
We are back to finish the job.
...至此哥特城就一蹶不振了
And this time no misguided idealists will get in the way.
我們這次來就是了結這一切的
Like your father, you lack the courage to do all that is necessary.
而這一次絕對不會有不得要領的理想主義者了
If someone stands in the way of true justice...
跟你父母一樣 你缺乏不惜一切代價的勇氣
...you simply walk up behind them and stab them in the heart.
如果有人阻擋正義的實現...
- I am gonna stop you. - You never did learn...
...就應該從他們的背後狠狠地捅上一刀
...to mind your surroundings.
-我要阻止你 -你還沒學會...
Justice is balance.
...眼觀六路耳聽八方
You burned my house and left me for dead.
正義是公平的
Consider us even.
你曾經燒了我的房子 和置我於死地
No one comes out. Make sure.
這下扯平了
GORDON: They're all gone?
不許任何人出來 明白？
- How many from maximum security? - Every one of them.
戈登:人都跑了
Serial killers, rapists.
-重點看護區跑了多少 -都跑了
Raise the bridges. We don't want any getting off the island.
連環殺手 強奸犯
FLASS: Yeah, I'll raise the bridges...
把吊橋吊起來 不能讓他們逃離這個島
...when I get every available unit out here to catch the homicidal maniacs...
福拉斯:好 我去吊吊橋...
...that are running loose out there. - Come on!
...我先去調集所有能調集的人馬...
I hope you're not a member of the fire brigade.
-...一起來這裡抓那些逃出去的瘋子 -快去吧
Master Wayne! Master Wayne!
但願你不是消防隊的
What is the point of all those pushups if you can't even lift a bloody log?
韋恩少爺！韋恩少爺！
[PLAYING PIANO]
你平時做的俯臥撐都白做了 連塊木頭都搬不動
BRUCE: What have I done, Alfred?
[鋼琴聲]
Everything my family...
布魯斯:我都干了些什麼呀？艾爾弗雷德
...my father, built...
我家的一切...
The Wayne legacy is more than bricks and mortar, sir.
...我父親親手建造的....
I wanted to save Gotham.
韋恩家族的遺產不僅僅是磚瓦 少爺
I failed.
我隻想拯救哥特城
Why do we fall, sir?
但我失敗了
So that we can learn to pick ourselves up.
為什麼說失敗 少爺？
You still haven't given up on me?
我們學會了“哪裡摔倒哪裡爬起來”
Never.
你還沒對我失去信心？
GORDON: Down!
永遠不會
MAN: Harassment! I see harassment!
戈登:給我下來
Maybe you'd like to see some excessive force?
強制執法 我是目擊證人
Madman with a gun.
也許你還想見識見識暴力執法吧
WOMAN [ON TV]: With residents furious...
拿槍就了不起呀
...at the unprecedented show of police strength to round up the inmates...
[電視報道]: 民眾對大量警察圍堵...
We're about to raise these bridges.
...精神病院病人的行為感到異常憤怒....
Officer, I am a Gotham City district attorney. Let me pass.
吊橋馬上起要起吊了
- Just shut up! - Hey, Flass, cool it!
警官 我是檢察院的 讓我過去吧
OFFICER 1: Hold these people back.
-你閉嘴 -嘿 福拉斯 別激動
OFFICER 2: Hey, Gordon. Somebody here to see you.
把圍觀者逼退回去
- What are you doing here? - Our friend sent me with this.
嘿 戈登 有人要見你
It counteracts Crane's toxin.
-你來這干嘛？ -我們的朋友讓我給你帶來這個
Hopefully you won't need it.
它能抵擋克蘭的致幻劑
Not unless he's got some way of getting that crap into the air.
希望你用不著它
All right, last one across.
除非能把它釋放到空氣中
OFFICER 1: People, they want this bridge up in no more than three minutes!
好吧，最後一個
Better get you off the island before they raise the bridges. Patrolman!
快一點 3分鐘之內就要起吊了
Go!
最好在吊橋升起來之前 把你護送出去 巡警
[PEOPLE SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
走
I can't find my mom.
[模糊的喊聲]
RACHEL: Hey!
我找不到我媽媽了
What the hell are you doing?
雷切爾:嘿！
DUCARD: Gentlemen...
你干什麼呢？
...time to spread the word.
杜卡德:先生們...
And the word is...
...現在到了傳播消息的時候
...panic.
這個消息就是...
Jesus. The pressure, it's spiking.
...痛苦
[BEEPING]
天哪 壓力突然增大了
Right there.
[嗶嗶聲]
MAN: That water main is right under the Narrows.
這
[PEOPLE COUGHING]
主要是窄島那裡
RACHEL: It's okay.
[咳嗽聲]
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
雷切爾:好了 沒關系
This is Commissioner Loeb.
[模糊的說話聲]
Come on, somebody talk to me.
我是雷波特派員
Come on!
請答話 請答話
GORDON: Loeb, Loeb. This is Gordon.
請答話！
What the hell is going on?
戈登:雷波 雷波 我是戈登
We need reinforcements. TAC teams, SWAT, riot cops!
告訴我出什麼事了？
Gordon! All the city's riot police are on the island with you!
我們需要增援 空軍 SWAT 防暴警察
GORDON [OVER RADIO]: Well, they're completely incapacitated!
戈登! 所有的警察都調到你那裡了
It's okay, it's okay. No one's gonna hurt you.
戈登 [無線電中] : 不錯 可他們都失去戰斗力了
SCARECROW: Of course they are!
沒事了 沒事了 誰也不會傷害到你的 沒事的
- Crane? - No. Scarecrow.
稻草人: 當然啦
Gordon...
-克蘭?. -不 我是稻草人
...there's nobody left to send in.
戈登...
GORDON: So I'm on my own?
...已經沒有人手了
The Narrows is tearing itself to pieces.
戈登:這麼說就隻能靠我自己了？
This is just the beginning. If they hit the whole city...
窄島已經毀滅得差不多了
...there's nothing to stop Gotham tearing itself apart.
這才剛剛開始 如果他們把致幻劑散播到全城的話...
- How are they gonna do that? - The train.
...那整個哥特城就玩完了
The monorail follows the water mains to the central hub beneath Wayne Tower.
-他們要怎麼干？ -他們要利用火車
If the machine gets to the station...
單軌鐵路順著供水系統可以 一直通向韋恩大廈的中央管道
...it'll cause a chain reaction that'll vaporize the city's water supply.
一旦他們把蒸發器放進韋恩火車站...
Covering Gotham in this poison.
...必將引起一系列的連鎖反應 最終將整個城市的自來水全部蒸發
I'm gonna stop him from loading that train, but I may need your help.
整個城市將籠罩在毒氣中
- What do you need? - Can you drive stick?
我去阻止他將武器運上火車 但我可能需要你的幫助
SCARECROW: There you are!
-你需要什麼？ -會開手動擋的車嗎？
There is nothing to fear...
稻草人:來吧
...but fear itself!
沒什麼可怕的...
I am here to help you!
...隻有恐懼本身
[SCARECROW SCREAMING]
我是來拯救你們的
Batman will save us. He'll come.
[稻草人慘叫聲]
- He'll come. - Don't peek.
蝙蝠俠會來救我們的 他一定會的
This is Gordon. Prepare to lower the bridge.
-他一定會來的 -別看
I told you he'd come.
我是戈登. 准備放吊橋
RACHEL: Wait.
我告訴過你他會來的
You could die.
雷切爾:等等
At least tell me your name.
你可能會喪命的
It's not who I am underneath...
至少告訴我你的名字
...but what I do that defines me.
這不是我過去如何的問題...
Bruce?
...重要的是我現在的表現
Well, well. You took my advice about theatricality a bit literally.
布魯斯?
- It ends here. - For you and the police, maybe.
可惜呀 可惜 你把我關於 戲劇性的建議表現得過於文學化了
My fight, however, lies with the rest of Gotham.
-該結束了 -對你和警察而言 也許如此
Now, if you'll excuse me, I have a city to destroy.
而我的戰爭 是和哥特城的戰爭
- I can't beat two of your pawns? - As you wish.
現在 請原諒 我要去摧毀城市了
COMPUTER: GPS online.
-我打不過你旁邊的兩個嗎？ -隨你的便吧
In 100 yards.
電腦:GPS系統啟動
DUCARD: Gentlemen.
距離100碼
Who the hell authorized this?
杜卡德:先生們
COMPUTER: Distance to Wayne Tower, three miles.
到底誰下的命令
The pressure's moving along the mains, blowing the pipes.
電腦:距韋恩大廈三英裡
If that pressure reaches us...
壓力沿主管線擴散 雅圖管道全部破裂
...the water supply right across the whole city is gonna blow!
如果壓力到達這裡...
COMPUTER: At the next intersection, turn right.
...全城的管道就全完了
You will never learn.
電腦:下一個區段右轉
Sorry.
你從不吸取教訓
- Familiar. Don't you have anything new? - How about this?!
不好意思
COMPUTER: You have arrived at Wayne Tower.
-老套子 你就沒有點新鮮的嗎？ -這個怎麼樣？
MAN: Evacuate the building.
電腦:你已經抵達韋恩大廈
We're on top of the main hub and it's gonna blow.
撤離大樓
COMPUTER: Weapons system activated.
我們坐落在上方的主管線 馬上就要爆裂了
Nice ride.
電腦:射擊系統准備就緒
COMPUTER: Armed.
好車
[BEEPING]
電腦:瞄准
Don't be afraid, Bruce.
[嗶嗶聲]
Come on. Come on.
別害怕 布魯斯.
DUCARD: You are just an ordinary man in a cape.
快點 快呀
That's why you couldn't fight injustice, that's why you can't stop this train.
杜卡德:你不過是個普通人
Who said anything about stopping it?
所以你無法與非正義抗衡 所以你無法阻止這列火車
Yes!
誰說要阻止它？
BATMAN: You never learned to mind your surroundings!
太好了
Have you finally learned to do what is necessary?
蝙蝠俠:你總是學不會眼觀六路耳聽八方
I won't kill you...
那你最終學會不惜一切代價了嗎？
...but I don't have to save you.
我不打算殺死你...
JESSICA: The meeting's already started. - What meeting?
...但我也不打算再救你一命
Fox, I seem to remember firing you.
杰西卡:會議已經開始了 -什麼會議？
You did.
福克斯 我記得我好像 已經把你開除了
I got another job.
確實如此
Yours.
我有找到了另一個職位
On whose authority?
你的職位
ALFRED: Batman may have made the front page...
誰任命的
...but Bruce Wayne got pushed to page eight.
艾爾弗雷德: 有關蝙蝠俠的新聞都是頭條...
[CELL PHONE RINGS]
...但是有關布魯斯.韋恩的新聞 隻能登在第八頁
Bruce Wayne.
[手機鈴聲]
What makes you think you can decide who's running Wayne Enterprises?
布魯斯.韋恩
- The fact that I'm the owner. EARLE: What are you talking about?
你怎麼會自己以為自己 有權經營韋恩集團呢?
The company went public a week ago.
-事實上我才是集團的擁有者 厄爾:你說什麼?
And I bought most of the shares.
集團一周前已經上市了
Through various charitable foundations and trusts and so forth.
我通過好幾個慈善機構和基金會
Look, it's all a bit technical, but the important thing...
購買了大部分的股份
...is that my company's future is secure.
你瞧 這麼說是不是技術上有點難懂 總之最重要的是...
Right, Mr. Fox?
...韋恩集團的未來有了保障
FOX: Right you are, Mr. Wayne.
對不對 福克斯?
Didn't you get the memo?
福克斯:對 韋恩先生
- I'm sorry I didn't tell you, Rachel. - No. No, Bruce...
你拿到備忘錄了嗎?
...I'm sorry.
-對不起 我沒有告訴你 雷切爾 -不不不 布魯斯...
The day that Chill died, I...
...應該說對不起的是我
I said terrible things.
切爾死的那一天 我....
But true things.
我說的話太傷人了
I was a coward with a gun...
但確實是實話
...and justice is about more than revenge, so thank you.
我是個拿著槍的懦夫...
I never stopped thinking about you.
...正義不僅僅是報仇 所以 我謝謝你
About us.
我一直在想著你
And when I heard you were back, I...
想著我們的事
I started to hope.
聽說你回來後 我....
But then I found out about your mask.
心裡又燃起了希望
Batman's just a symbol, Rachel.
後來我發現了你就是蝙蝠俠
No. This...
蝙蝠俠隻是一個象征, 雷切爾.
...is your mask.
不 那是...
Your real face is the one that criminals now fear.
...是你的面具
The man I loved...
現在罪犯們懼怕的是真正的你
...the man who vanished...
我以前所愛的...
...he never came back at all.
...那個失蹤的你...
But maybe he's still out there somewhere.
...根本就沒有再回來
Maybe someday, when Gotham no longer needs Batman...
也許他就在外面某個地方
...I'll see him again.
也許有那麼一天 當哥特城不再需要蝙蝠俠的時候...
- Proved me wrong, you know. - About what?
...我又能再見到他
Your father would be very proud of you.
-我承認我以前錯了 -關於什麼?
Just like me.
我是說你的父親一定會為你感到自豪
RACHEL: What will you do?
就像我一樣感到自豪
Rebuild it.
雷切爾:你打算將來怎麼辦?
Just the way it was, brick for brick.
重建庄園
Just the way it was, sir?
恢復它從前的一磚一瓦
Yeah, why?
和從前的一模一樣?
I thought this might be a good opportunity for...
你是什麼意思?
...improving the foundations.
我是說這是個難得的機會...
- In the southeast corner? - Precisely, sir.
...應該重新完善一下地基
- Nice. - I couldn't find any mob bosses.
-你是說東南角？ -對極啦
BATMAN: Well, sergeant? - It's "lieutenant" now.
-怎麼樣？ -我連一個黑幫老大都見不到
You really started something.
蝙蝠俠:是嗎？上校 -現在是“中校”了
Bent cops running scared.
你干的真不錯
Hope on the streets.
壞警察都聞風喪膽了
- But? - The Narrows is lost.
街道上也充滿了希望
And we still haven't picked up Crane or half the inmates of Arkham that he freed.
-還有呢？ -不過窄島完了
We will.
我們還沒有抓到克蘭 還有被他釋放的一大半其他病人
We can bring Gotham back.
會抓住他們的
- What about escalation? - Escalation?
我要重建哥特城
We start carrying semiautomatics, they buy automatics.
-犯罪率增加怎麼辦？ -增加？
We start wearing Kevlar, they buy armor-piercing rounds.
我們開始用半自動武器時 罪犯們已經用上全自動的了
- And? - And you're wearing a mask...
而當我們開始穿上防彈服的時候 他們卻用起了金屬爆裂子彈
...and jumping off rooftops.
-還有嗎？ -還有當你帶著面具...
Now, take this guy.
...從屋頂上跳下來的時候
Armed robbery, double homicide.
琢磨琢磨這家伙
Got a taste for the theatrical, like you.
持槍搶劫犯 雙料殺人犯
Leaves a calling card.
喜歡戲劇性 跟你一樣
I'll look into it.
留下一張牌
I never said thank you.
這件事交給我吧
And you'll never have to.
我從未謝過你
沒有這個必要